Back in 2009, your Aunt Robin got
a job hosting a morning show.
Which meant she had
to get up kind of early.
How early?
'Morning everybody.
So you actually doing it?
You're actually going to work
at 2:00 a.m.?
I'm not doing it for me,
I'm doing it for the fans.
Who exactly are the fans of a show
that airs at 4:00 in the morning?
People getting up to host a show
at 5:00 in the morning.
Meth addicts who haven't sold
their TVs yet?
Strippers in that
messy gray area between
getting off work and
getting their kids up for school?
Them's my peeps.
All right, catch me up.
What's been going on?
You know...
The yoozh.
Really, the yoozh?
Think of the funniest thing
that has ever happened.
- Got it.
- Now double that.
So, a chimpanzee wearing
two texudos.
Something even funnier than that
happen's to Marshall today.
Okay, first of all,
there's nothing funnier than that.
Second of all, look it's...
It's not that good a story.
Come on, you guys,
you're four young active people living
in the most exciting city on earth.
You're telling me you have
no stories for me?
What can I say?
Some weeks are just like that.
It's the same thing over and over.
A kid in my class ate some paste.
I used deceitful means to hook up
with a less-than-intelligent girl.
My ex-gilfriend Karen moved to town,
it's just all the same Robin.
Karen's in town?
- Oh noooo!
- You have got to be kidding me!
Kids, I think I've
told you about Karen.
She was my girlfriend in high-school,
and intermittently through college.
She was beautiful, smart.
I was madly in love with her.
The only problem was,
Marshall and Lily were not.
I think it had something to do
were every time Karen opened her mouth.
I love taht you guys live in a dorm.
It's so American.
It's like let's all eat baloney
sandiwches and be racist.
Oh my God. She was such a douche.
Dude, she was the heiress
of the Massengill fortune.
She really wasn't that bad.
Of course, you think that
she turned you into one of
her douche zombies.
I want to eat your brain
but only if it's organic
and grass-fed.
What?
Will you pass the salt?
Salt?
So bourgeois.
Totally.
What's that thing?
That's... a TV, Karen.
I don't watch TV.
Totally.
You thought I actually bought
tickets to Wrestle Mania?
I was being ironic.
Totally.
I know
that you were being ironic.
I too...
I'm being ironic.
Let's do this.
What?
That make up didn't
come off for a month.
I had to meet Lily's parents that way.
I've never looked like a bigger jackass.
Until today, tell the story...
Just let it go.
Well, hold on.
Is it really funny?
I am not kidding you.
I almost don't want you to hear it,
because seriously,
for the rest of your life,
nothing else will ever be as funny
and you
will curse yourself for agreeing
to ever hear it in the first place.
But seriously, you got to hear it,
it's so funny.
Fine.
I was at the compagny gym this
morning, playing basketball, and
the guys I work with can be
pretty brutal with their ridicule.
Look at Wisniewski.
He's gonna cry, look at him.
I don't know. I don't think knees aren't
supposed to bend that way, I think
he might have tore his ACL.
The only thing that guy tore was
his cervix or maybe his hymen.
Yeah, or his fallopian tube.
I may have cleaned up
the dialogue a little bit.
Anyways...
I go to my duffle bag
to get out my work clothes.
Wait, wait!
I want to say it...
Fine, you say it.
Marshall goes to his duffle bag
to get out his work clothes
and... No, no, no, you say it.
It's funnier if you say it.
No, let me say it!
No, you say it.
You say it. Say it.
Same time!
No, no, no. You go, you go!
- I forgot...
- Marshall forgot his pants!
He forgot his pants.
Marshhal forget his pants,
That's pretty funny.
It's not a chimpanzee
wearing two tuxedos.
What? Did he...
forgot he put the first one on?
Stupid monkey!
So Karen in New York,
weird, right?
Ted, you cannot get back together
with Karen.
I nerver said I was going to get back
together with her.
I was thinking
she's new in town, would it be the worst
thing in the world if I gave her a call?
It wouldn't be the worst thing
in the world,
it would be the fourth worst thing.
Number 1, Super volcano.
Number 2, an astroid hits the Earth.
Number 3,
all footage of Evel Knievel is lost.
Number 4, Ted calls Karen.
Number 5,
Lily gets eaten by a shark.
I'm Lily and I approve
the order of that list.
You don't know the whole story.
Ted and Karen were off and on
all through college,
and it always went the same way.
They'd be having fun,
douching it up, and then one day...
I know you think pepperoni is fascist
and you're totally right, so I can...
Oh, my God! Karen!
Sorry, bro.
Before you say anything,
I think that you should read.
Baudelaire's, "Les Fleurs Du Mal".
So then they break up,
He would be all depressed, and
we would wait
the appropriate amount of time
and then we'd would tell him
how we really felt.
- Karen and I broke up.
- We hated her!
Bitch had to go!
And then Ted would build up
a head of steam
and finally take the bus to Providence
to give Karen a piece of his mind.
How did it go?
Great.
Look who's back?
And then sure enough, the whole
thing would start all over again.
Make that 10000 and 2 Maniacs, because
I got us Natalie Merchant tick...
Sorry, bro.
So she would come visit you at school
and the second you turned your back
she would bring guys
back to your dorm room?
Respect.
I was an idiot.
She was my first real girlfriend,
She was madly in love with her.
We all did stuff we regret,
in college.
Junior year,
Marshall grew a soul patch,
wore a rasta hat, and asked
everyone to call him M.J. Smooth.
I don't regret that for one second.
So you guys, absolutely
don't think I should call her?
- Ted, no!
- What's wrong with you?
Fine I won't.
Interristing piece of trivia,
- I called her.
- What are you doing?
It's the pants story.
I can't believe you called her.
Why don't you just ask her
to lunch while you're at it?
Because, Lily, I'm not gonna
ask her out to lunch
again.
You asked her to lunch?
Why would anyone,
want to have a lunch,
- with their ex.
- Glad you asked, Marshall.
There are four possible motives
behind an ex lunch.
Number 1, they want to
get back together.
Like my high school
boyfriend Scooter.
Lilies, clever.
I'm sorry I don't have
a scooter for you.
My God, that's funny.
I forgot how funny you are.
- Where is the waiter?
- Why?
You like waiters?
I can be a waiter.
I'm going to be the greatest waiter
on this earth, and then you'll love me.
Number 2, they want to kill you.
Like when I had lunch with Wendy.
I'm glad we could finally do this.
You know, after that ninth time
you rescheduled on me?
I almost gave up on you.
But you didn't.
You just kept on trying.
By the way
there's something
I've been meaning to give you.
Gun! She's got a gun!
It's a tie.
Number 3, they actually do
want to give you your stuff back.
Like when I had lunch with Curt.
By the way, there's something
I've been meaning to give you?
My snub-nosed. 38 police special.
I knew I left that somewhere.
Every time I watch the news, I'm like,
"Hope that wasn't my gun."
Breaking up was the right choice.
Or number 4, to rub your face
in how great they're doing.
Like my lunch with Nicole Barsamian.
- Who's Nicole Barsamian?
- My ex.
Hello Nicole.
You look well, Marshall.
You look okay, I guess.
- I'm seing someone.
- Already?
Who?
Lee Roberts.
He reads at a fifth grade level.
You have to cancel the lunch.
I would definitetly do that,
definitetly.
Except I already had it.
I'm going to need to borrow
the butt of your gun.
I actually lost it again.
Can you believe that?
How could you break bread
with that woman?
It was just lunch.
And you know she doesn't eat wheat.
We had great time, catching up.
We even laughed about
what jerks we were back then.
I can't believe I had a beret
for each day of the week.
I can't believe I had an iron-on
image of Molière on my backpack.
Man, we were pretentious.
So pretentious.
What can I get you?
I don't want to cause a scene
but your wine list has
a Châteauneuf du Pape
listed under the Côte de Provence.
You might want to alert your sommelier.
And, for you?
I hate to go off-menu but,
can you bring us some
brochette with
fresh mozzarella? Grazie.
It was great. It was great.
There was one, weird moment,
towards the end.
How do you say good-bye
in those situations?
A kiss on the cheek is too familiar,
a handshake is too formal...
A hug is just like
a public dry hump.
I think you're hugging wrong.
- So what happenned?
- Well...
Schopenhauer made
a saucy little argument,
in which, he pos...
Ted, honey, I want you to go outside and
bite the curb. I'll be out in a minute.
Karen, was the first girl
I ever loved.
Okay? And, after the year I've had,
I don't know, I guess,
having lunch with her just
remind me of what it was like to be 18
and have my whole life figured out.
And I would like to remind everyone,
that at least,
I was wearing pants, Marshall!
You can't just go changing
the subject like that!
The pants story.
Pants story bomaye!
There is no story!
I had a little situation
- so I called Lily.
- Refresh us,
- what was that situation?
- I forgot my pants.
What do you mean,
you forgot your pants?
I forgot them.
I need you to bring me some.
What about your spare pants?
Last thursday, the mustard incident?
Jeez, woman, you have
the memory of a goldfish!
You're not getting off that easy!
Marshall's pants story,
while amusing...
Amusing? Try... Very amusing.
Is nothing compared to this
Karen madness. Finish your story.
Taht's it! It was just
one kiss in the restaurant.
Why did you say "in the restaurant"?
Did you kiss somewhere else?
Like where?
In a tree?
Lily, we did not make out in a tree!
What's with this one?
What did you do?
Ted, how could you?
Marshall forgot to bring
his pants to work today
and you're still the stupidest person
at this table.
Okay, Lily, let's be honest.
We both know
your real motivation here,
you hate Karen,
because, she lingered.
You son of a bitch!
What do you mean, she lingered?
February 5, 1998.
I was painting.
Sorry, I...
Sorry... I...
You know...
Thaht color palette is a bit
derivative of early Van Gogh,
don't you think?
Cheat on Ted, criticize my painting,
whatever that's your business.
But I catch you,
peeping on my man's junk,
and you linger!
You gots to get got!
The game is the game.
In Karen's defense,
I had just worked out.
Why did you have to paint
Marshall nude anyway?
Because he ate my bowl of fruit.
But the point is, Karen,
is a dirty linger
and you cannot bring
her back into our lives!
Relax! It was just that one night!
And the next three after that.
And one morning.
But at least,
I had pants on, Marshall.
Although, actually, I didn't.
Wait. This happen in our appartment?
Where was I?
You know, those sleeping pills you're
taking to keep on
your crazy new schedule?
I think they're stronger
than you realize.
La Fontaine gets
the puck to Turgeon.
Turgeon shoots.
Glove save!
Hey, Ted. Hey, Lily.
Don't worry, I won't tell Marshall.
I'm gonna grab a beer, you want one?
Beer!
I'll start decanting the Bordeaux.
Sure it's fun to look back at a time
when you were a fresh-faced
farm girl with a virgin's glow.
But all that stuff,
Ohio, Karen, college?
All that was B.S.
Before Stinson.
Now, your life is awesome!
I mean, yeah,
you still live with your ex-girlfriend
which is ridiculous.
Your Laser Tag chops
are almost nonexistent.
And your wardrobe!
It's like
what, are you allergic to quality
fabrics? Seriously Ted, shape up!
What were we talking about?
So what's next with this broad?
Please, the story is already written.
Ted is Charlie Brown,
trying to kick the football
and Karen's Lucy, who pulls it away at
the last second and has sex with it.
You guys know what I mean.
Ted's gonna fall in love and then
Karen's gonna cheat on him
with some meathead who's like.
Sorry, bro.
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
You must have left the right answer
in your pants Marshall,
cause that's exactly
what didn't happen.
You guys, here' what happenned.
One afternoon,
we were at Karen's place...
Oh, my God!
How could you?
Sorry, bro.
So this time, the meathead
Karen was cheating with...
Was me.
Me.
Remember that time
Marshall forgot his pants?
You quit trying to change the subject.
You crossed the line.
You are complicit in breaking
some poor guy's heart. And you,
you of all people know
exactly how that feels.
You really don't want to tell
the pants story?
- What?
- Pants, pants...
Fine!
Lily came down to the office
to bring me my pants...
- Why did she have to do that?
- Because I forgot my pants.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to give Marshall something.
Here to give him something.
Gotcha. Nice.
But I'm in a hurry.
Can I just give it to you?
Sure.
And then you'll give it to him?
Wait. I don't know about all that.
I mean,
yours would have to be really good.
- What are you talking about?
Marshall forgot his pants,
so I'm bringing him a new pair.
Marshall forgot his pants.
It's a good thing that you came by
because he has a really
important meeting today,
and it would be pretty embarrassing
and not at all funny if he were
to show up not wearing pants.
- I'll make sure he gets these.
- Great. Thanks.
And you didn't give him his pants.
Of course I gave him his pants.
I gave Lily my word. My word is oak.
Though I did make some alterations.
Now, as you'll see on page 44
of the contract...
When did you join AC/DC?
Now, can we please just turn
to page 44 of the contract.
I think the Oliver Twist auditions
are down the hall!
Please, sir, may I have some more...
pants?
More pan...
That's it? That's the whole story?
- So what happened with Karen?
- I'll finish it for you.
Ted left without saying anything and
Karen got exactly what she wanted.
Not this time.
You have a boyfriend?
We've been drifting
apart for a long time.
I've been meaning to
break up with him.
You are unbelievable.
You don't have the guts
to break up with someone
like a decent human being,
so instead you pull this crap.
You're right.
I'm great with books.
I'm great with art.
I'm great with
identifying French wines
from within a mile of where
the grapes are grown. But...
I'm really bad when it comes
to looking someone in the eye
and telling them the truth
about how I feel.
We're both bad at that. But...
I think we both need to change. So,
why don't I go first?
You're a really hurtful
and reckless person, and
I never want to see you
or speak to you again.
Au revoir.
Wait.
Actually,
"au revoir"means "until
we see each other again".
So, I'm assuming that you mean
we will in fact
see each other again?
Sorry, bro.
I am impressed with you.
You, too, Marshall.
Have you been wearing those all day?
They show off my calves.
Pants story. Tell it again.
Maybe it was good you called Karen.
It definitely was.
And not just for me, but for her, too.
Later that night,
she sat down with Jerry,
and she had the break-up talk
she always avoided with me.
So you see, kids,
sometimes when you have
to have a tough conversation,
the best thing to do...
Wait
a second.
You said you were never gonna talk
to Karen again, right?
Then how do you know
she took your advice?
Well, about that...
After she broke up with that dude, she
called me, we went out, we hooked up,
we've been dating ever since.
We're really seeing eye to eye,
it just feels different somehow.
Here she comes now. Be cool!