Kids, the day you get married
is supposed to be
the happiest day of your life,
the perfect ending
to a perfect love story.
My wedding...
at least my first wedding
didn't go so well.
It's funny looking back on it now.
I was so sure Stella was the one.
And when she left me,
I was so devastated.
But you guys got me through it.
And now the painful part's over.
I've come out the other side
a little bit stronger.
You know, I hardly even
think about her anymore.
That's what time does, I guess.
Ted, the wedding was yesterday.
It's been 24 hours.
I know.
And this is me, moving on.
A great new chapter
of my life began today,
and we're gonna celebrate.
Right now,
we need two things.
We need Kool,
and we need the Gang.
It's jukebox time, huh?
I look at that young man
popping and locking his way over
to the jukebox,
and I think to myself,
you know
maybe Stella made the right call.
Pain.
How is he dancing right now?
He should be smashing up.
Stella's car with a sledgehammer.
Hypothetical.
Ted isn't pretending to be happy.
Ted really is happy.
He never wanted to get married
in the first place.
Ted just pulled off
the greatest train dodge
since Stand by Me.
Well, not the first kid,
but the other kids.
No, he is in bad shape.
What's up?
Really bad shape.
And we need to be there for him.
But as much as my friends
wanted to be there for me,
I was, by all appearances
fine.
- Hey, buddy.
- Want to hang out?
Guys, I'm fine.
Hey, pal, you want to have a catch?
I'm fine.
Hey, kiddo.
This is not necessary, and
it's actually kind of weird.
No offense, ladies.
I did not realize you'd be home.
Ladies, to the stairwell.
Finally, after two weeks,
the inevitable emotions boiled over.
Hey, you guys want to get some dinner?
Oh, shut up.
I'm sorry, sweetie. It's just...
Ted, you've been through
something traumatic,
and we're trying to
be there for you as friends,
but you're not letting us,
and it's pissing us off,
you selfish bitch.
Sorry.
Look, we're just worried that you're not
dealing with this whole Stella thing.
Okay? Do you remember
when Lily left me?
You remember how
I held in my feelings?
I...
miss
her so much.
Yeah, dude, you were a rock.
Well, I should have been
even worse, okay?
I should have gotten mad.
I should have taken your advice
and set all of Lily's stuff on fire.
Oh, nice. Thanks, Ted.
But I didn't,
and I think that that's why
it took me so long to get better.
So, now, Ted...
I want you to explode.
Release the berserker.
Okay, ready?
Now!
- I'm good.
- No.
Guys, get off his back.
He's happy.
Listen, if Ted were married right now,
he'd be married, he'd be living
in New Jersey, and
he'd be married.
He's fine. Now, let's eat.
How about Flat Michael's?
No, that's 44th and Lex.
Can't do it.
Why not?
It's too close to Stella's gym.
Might run into her.
Anywhere else, though.
Okay... how about Hurley's?
Right between Stella's office
and her dry cleaners.
No, sir.
Well, what about meat loaf Charlie's?
Two blocks
from Stella's mother's hairdressers.
Well, geez, Ted, is there anywhere
in Manhattan we can go to dinner?
Of course.
Check this out.
What you got there, Ted?
A little reference map
I made for myself.
A New York guide to places you
might run into Stella Zinman.
Red areas are places to avoid.
White areas are safe.
Blue is water.
That is just ridiculous.
Well, water is blue.
You can't live that way.
She leaves you at the altar,
and you're the one avoiding her?
Yes, I'm avoiding her.
What's the big deal?
That's how we do it.
Who's we, gutless weenies?
No, "we" is people
from the great state of Ohio.
When life gives us pain,
we Buckeyes take that pain
and we push it down.
And if the pain starts
to come up again,
we push more pain down on top of it.
Why confront something
when you can avoid it, right?
All I have to do
is never see Stella again,
and I'll live a long, happy life.
Now, who wants to get something to eat?
Oh, somebody just told me about
a tapas place
that's in the white zone.
Great. Let's go there.
You ready to order?
Not quite yet.
Can we get some of those almonds
for the table?
Certainly.
Nice call, Lily.
This place looks great.
Who told you about it?
You know, I don't remember.
What?
I'd just remember.
Oh, my God.
Okay, just be cool.
We're just gonna have
to deal with this.
Everyone
follow my lead.
- You're kidding.
- Is he serious?
I am not getting under this table.
I'd maybe get under that table.
She's turning around.
Think.
Everyone, just stay here.
I'm gonna go take a look.
Marshall, go take a look.
And will you need utensils?
No, I'm just going straight home.
She's placing an order to go.
Did she seem happy?
Did she say anything about me?
I don't even care.
Where are those almonds?
Gosh, where would Ted's nuts be?
Hey, why don't you check
the vise in Stella's garage?
Go yell at her.
Ted, you may be from Ohio,
but you live in New York now.
We don't push down
our feelings in New York.
We take our feelings and we shove them
in somebody else's face!
Oh, spare me, Lily.
You'd be doing the same thing
if you were in this situation.
That's outrageous.
There is not a person on Earth
I would hide under a table from.
Really, not a single person?
Not even...
Gasser?
How dare you mention that name to me.
Who's Gasser?
He's the last person I'd want to see
walk through that door.
Michael Sasser.
He's a guy I went to high school with.
Michael sat next to me
in freshman biology.
He had been a bit of a loser
all through middle school,
but the summer before ninth grade,
he grew 12 inches
and joined the baseball team.
He was right on the precipice
of becoming one of the cool kids.
Until one day...
We've all been there.
When you've ripped one,
it's not pretty.
What did you do?
Are you kidding?
This was ninth grade.
I only had one choice.
Oh, my God, Sasser. Fart much?
No, it wasn't me. It was her.
As if, Sasser.
More like Gasser.
Gasser!
I'm on the baseball team.
I'm cool.
The nickname Gasser stuck.
He got teased so much, eventually
he had to change schools.
Kids are awesome.
I've always felt awful about that.
But if Gasser...
Michael
walked in right now,
as hard as it would be,
I would go up to Gasser...
Michael,
and I would resolve things between us.
Right, clear the air, as it were.
Oh, man.
Those don't come around often.
Y'all are welcome.
- Hey, are you guys okay?
- Oh, yeah.
We're just gonna be eating down here
if that's okay.
Well, here's your almonds.
Thanks...
you guys have any specials today?
Ted, this is ludicrous.
Ted, I am a person who...
Well, let's just face it.
There are a lot of people
I don't want to see
people of the
"chicks I banged" persuasion,
but if any of them were to walk in here,
I would stand up,
and I would look them right in the eye.
Some of them for the very first time.
Really, you wouldn't hide from anyone?
Not even, say...
Becca Delucci?
You son of a bitch.
Who's Becca Delucci?
Do you mind?
So, who is Becca Delucci?
Becca is just this
girl who lives upstate.
I used to visit her now and again.
Where exactly upstate, Barney?
Bedford Hills Federal Penitentiary.
And yes, the visits were
of a conjugal nature.
- No way, really?
- Really.
And what I had with Becca
was a perfect relationship.
She was only allowed, by law,
to call me once a week.
If she ever got clingy,
the armed guards stopped her.
And I never had to pay for dinner.
Well, that's not true.
I pay taxes.
Then again, I guess
we all paid for dinner.
Thanks a lot, guys.
Anyway, the last time I visited,
I kind of screwed things up.
I know it's hard, baby,
but I'm in a prison, too.
A prison of my own heart.
Is that room ready yet or what?
Can we...? Tick-tock.
Barney, you're the only thing
that's keeping me going here.
That's what I'm here for, baby.
I'm your rock.
I'm... oh, my God.
Hello, strange.
Barney Stinson, attorney at law.
- Let's talk about getting you off.
- Oh, hell, no!
Now I get letters from Becca
and she's all,
"I'm coming to get you the day
I get out of here.
I'm gonna hang your eyes
from my rearview mirror."
Women, huh?
See?
You're scared of Becca.
Lily's scared of Gasser.
We're staying under the table.
We don't have to.
- Stella's gone.
- Oh, my gosh.
There, all done,
and that's how we do it Ohio style.
Problem showed up. We avoided it.
It went away.
Now we can enjoy our meal
- in peace and...
- She's back.
Ted, we all think that you need...
Wait, where's Barney?
We all think that you need
to go talk to her.
- I don't.
- What?
Yeah, if the last person I wanted to see
walked through the door,
I wouldn't say a damn word.
- Really?
- And who's that?
My father.
You guys, that other table
is off the hook.
- What are we talking about?
- Robin's dad.
I haven't spoken to him in three years
and I don't intend to start now.
Why?
It goes back to the day I was born.
You give me my son now. Push.
He wanted a son
and the fact that I was a girl
didn't change his plan.
What do you mean?
My full legal name is
Robin Charles Scherbatsky, Jr.
And it only gets worse from there.
When I was eight, he took me
hunting for the first time.
I don't want to shoot a deer.
Nonsense, R.J.
Shooting deer
is the noblest of pursuits.
But they're cute.
You said the same thing
about our rabbits.
Remember how delicious they were?
Over the years, as my body developed...
Hold on a sec.
Sorry, go on.
It became harder and harder for him
to pretend I was a boy.
The lowest moment came
when I turned 14.
My peewee hockey team had just
won the Squamish Invitational
and everyone came back
to my house to celebrate.
You lads availed yourself
splendidly out there on the ice.
Splendidly.
You go on outside.
I'll come back with an assortment
of soft drinks
and American pretzels.
I can't believe you missed that
last empty-netter, you hoser.
- You're the hoser.
- No, you're the hoser.
What are you doing?
You're teammates,
hockey players.
Teammates don't kiss!
Hockey players don't kiss!
Oh, my God.
I have no son.
You poor thing.
To have to grow up in Canada
with America right there.
That sucks about your dad, Robin,
but congratulations on that game.
And Kyle and I weren't even doing
anything serious.
We only went to the blue line.
- Blue line?
- Yeah.
You know how when you're a kid,
you put everything into hockey terms?
The blue line is kissing,
the red line is getting naked,
and I think "in the crease" speaks
for itself.
Anyway, after that,
my relationship with my dad
pretty much went north.
I moved in with my mom,
grew my hair out,
became a Canadian pop star.
You know, normal teen stuff.
Don't you think it would feel better
to talk to him about all this?
No, that's the point.
It wouldn't solve anything.
It's in the past. It's done.
I mean, what would I even say to him?
"I wish you hadn't raised me as a boy"?
"I wish you hadn't taught me
how to hunt
and fish and smoke cigars
and drink Scotch
because that's not what girls do.
And you know the reason
I throw like a girl, Dad,
"is because I am a girl."
You held onto that for a long time?
It really messed you up.
- That sucks.
- I'm sorry.
It's hot.
And then I realized
all of my friends were haunted,
but there was a difference
between my ghost and theirs.
It wasn't too late for me.
I'm gonna go talk to her.
She's gone.
- I'm going after her.
- Go, go, go.
There she goes!
Okay, I see her.
She's two cabs ahead on the right.
Just stay with her, okay?
Finally.
Finally, you're doing this.
You're going to confront her.
- Yes, I am going to confront her.
- Yeah.
- This is so exciting.
- Totally.
What are you going to say?
I'm gonna say, "Stella,
I'm sorry things didn't work out."
We're going to talk
about this like adults.
She can tell me her side and...
I'm going to listen.
Probably should have done
a little more of that before.
Driver, can you run us
into the nearest lamppost?
Everyone, buckle up.
Not you, Ted.
Ted, you got to get mad right now.
Come on.
Dig deep.
Dude, come on.
This isn't about me waving my arms,
stamping my feet,
and getting really mad.
This is about Stella and I
finally communicating.
- I mean, clearly, that was...
- Stella hated Star Wars.
She lied to you.
Search your feelings, Ted.
You know it to be true.
Well, that's her business.
Come on, Ted.
She left you at the altar.
I don't understand!
Ted, in the name of all
that is sacred...
Wait!
Where is she going?
Her cab just missed the turn
for the Lincoln Tunnel.
Why would anybody buy take out food
and bring it all the way back
to New Jersey anyway?
Maybe she's going to her office.
The waiter asked her,
"Will you need utensils?"
And then she said, "No,
I'm just going straight home."
But if she's going home,
why are we still heading...
Oh, my God.
Tony lives downtown.
"Home"
is Tony's apartment.
She was going to make me
move to New Jersey
and then she moves into the city
with Tony?!
Son of a bitch!
- I am so angry right now!
- I know, and I love it!
Yeah, that is awesome!
Sir, we'd be happy to cover
the cost of that window crank.
I love angry Ted!
So do I!
Get it out, baby. Let it out.
She's stopping.
- It is on. It is on!
- Yes, Ted.
- Go get her, buddy!
- Go get rid of your demons!
- My leg is asleep!
- Okay, wa-wa-wait.
- Wait, hold on.
- Lily, what are you doing?
All right, hold on.
Look, Ted,
it's great
- that you're angry right now.
- It sure is.
And that you're finally dealing
with this, but
you only get one shot here.
Let's just take a beat and,
and think about
what you're going to say.
Oh, I know exactly what I'm gonna say.
You picked the wrong guy.
You made a really,
really,
really bad choice.
What were you thinking?
That guy?
Are you kidding me?
Have you learned nothing
in the last eight years?
You're just gonna regret this.
You know that, right?
You are going to regret this,
and now there is nothing
you can do about it
because it's too late.
All you can do now is go up there
and start your crappy,
disappointing life
that will never be nearly as happy
as the one you could have had with me.
Good-bye.
- Ted, wait.
- Look, Stella,
I am not here to win you back.
I am here because
I need to know
that you know
you made the biggest mistake
of your life.
I know.
Good.
That's what I'm gonna say.
- Dag!
- Cold-blooded.
Yeah, that's good. Go say that.
Thanks.
So I got out of the cab,
ready to say all of that stuff,
ready to explode,
but then...
- Mommy!
- Hey.
It all just went away.
And that was it.
In that moment, I wasn't angry anymore.
I could see Stella was meant
to be with Tony.
Kids, you may think
your only choices
are to swallow your anger
or throw it in someone's face.
There's a third option:
You can just let it go,
and only when you do that
is it really gone,
and you can move forward.
And that, kids,
was the perfect ending
to a perfect love story.
It just wasn't mine.
Mine was still out there
waiting for me.