OLDER TED: Kids, up to
this point in the story,
we had found doppelgangers,
eerie but
awesome look-alikes,
for four of
the five members
of our little group.
There was
Lesbian Robin...
(SPITTING)
Mustache Marshall,
Stripper Lily...
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
And Mexican Wrestler Me.
Yes, mine was the coolest.
And so, we were all
eager to find the fifth
doppelganger, Barney's.
Turned out it was
more important to
some of us than others.
We agree there's no sense
in having a baby
until we've seen all five
doppelgangers, right?
Of course.
Stands to reason.
Okay, so, when we finally
see Barney's doppelganger,
that's the universe
telling us it's go time,
and that's when
we'll start trying. Deal?
Deal.
OLDER TED:
And then one day,
a few weeks later...
Baby, were you serious
about the whole fifth
doppelganger thing?
I mean, having a baby
is a pretty big thing to
leave up to the universe.
Yeah, I know it's crazy.
It's just so much easier
to let the universe decide.
Why do you ask?
Boom! Universed!
Oh, my God! Wait,
wait, wait, hold on.
That could easily be
Barney pulling some
scam to meet chicks.
I'm one step
ahead of you.
Go for Barney.
Barney, hey,
it's Marshall.
So, you are at work?
You're not, I don't know,
driving a cab, wearing a wig?
Yes, I'm at work.
That's the sound
of my stapler.
That's the sound of
my three-hole punch.
And this is the sound
of me filing
my corporate guidelines
on sexual harassment.
What is up?
Gotta go, Big Chief.
Barney's at work.
That was the
fifth doppelganger.
(SIGHING)
Marshall Eriksen,
put a baby in my belly.
I can't wait
to tell the gang.
This is one
of those moments
you dream about.
"Guys, Lily and I
"are having unprotected sex."
Ooh, I just got the chills.
We're not gonna
say anything.
What? Why?
Marshall, if we tell them,
we're basically inviting them
into the most private,
intimate moment of our lives.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You guys banging?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Keep going.
I'm not even here.
But just for the record,
having a baby, huge mistake.
Now show me
what you got.
Uncle Teddy's here!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Quick question. How are
you guys gonna handle
the whole Santa thing?
I'm thinking,
just be honest.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, hell.
I'll dress up.
"This just in"
(BOTH SCREAMING)
is what Marshall Eriksen
is about to say to his wife
as he attempts
to impregnate her.
Chopper 12
is live on the scene
with Baby Watch: 2010.
(CHOPPER BLADES WHIRRING)
Okay, fine.
I won't tell anybody
about the baby thing.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
Guys, we saw the
fifth doppelganger!
(GASPING) Amazing!
Whoa! That is awesome!
Ooh! Freaky.
A brunette Barney.
I know. Say what you
will about the guy,
but Barney seems
right as a blond.
Well, that's true.
Not every dude can
pull off that blond look.
I don't know
about that.
What?'
That summer
I was lifeguarding at the
Chagrin Falls Country Club,
I was lathering
a little lemon juice
into the old mop,
playing with some
natural highlights.
Let's just say
there were a few
senior citizens
who pretended to
drown on my watch.
And sadly,
one who did.
Anyway,
I'd look good blond.
MARSHALL: Okay, people,
we're in a delicate
but very, very
promising situation here.
LILY: If we play
the next 30 seconds right,
Ted will dye his hair blond.
ROBIN: Guys, this is mean.
We can't...
Whoa! Just pictured it.
How do we do this?
TED: What are we all
thinking about? Nachos?
MARSHALL: Ted Mosby responds
to one thing above all else.
TED: I don't know.
I'm still kind of
full from lunch.
MARSHALL: A bunch of people
emphatically telling him
not to do something.
Follow my lead.
TED: Screw it.
I could eat.
Yes, we'd all
like some nachos.
I love you, buddy,
but there is
absolutely no way
that you could
pull off blond.
Yeah, it just
wouldn't look right.
Yeah. Seriously, Ted,
don't go blond.
I'm going blond.
No.
No way.
That is not the outcome
we were hoping for.
OLDER TED: Now, kids,
Robin and Don were becoming
such a great team,
both off and on the air,
that Local Channel 12
started asking them
to guest-host
some of their other
top-notch programs.
* Monty and Moo-Moo
are laughing and
learning with you
* Moo-Moo
Moo!
So, that's why
Monty and I vowed
never to do drugs,
because drugs are bad.
Right, Monty?
Well, sure.
Man-made, chemical stuff.
But things that
grow in nature,
they're okay to try,
like, once or twice.
Not looking for
gray areas here, Monty.
I don't think
it's right to lie
to the kids, Moo-Moo.
So, what are you saying?
I've experimented
with drugs.
(GASPING)
OLDER TED: Fun fact,
highest rated
Monty and Moo-Moo
episode ever.
ROBIN: Mmm.
Mmm. What was that for?
Before I met you,
I'd given up
on everything,
relationships,
career, pants.
But you made me
wanna try again.
I love you for that.
Oh.
Ooh! Oh, I see. Mmm.
(CHUCKLING)
Hi. Hey. Hi.
Sorry, you don't know me,
but I just wanted to say
thank you.
You're actually
a very important
person in my life.
Important? More like
legendary. Marshall,
it's me, Barney.
OLDER TED: Oddly enough,
this would rank as only
the second biggest
surprise of the day.
Wow, this is just
very sudden.
Sure, I can get you
an answer by tomorrow.
Okay. Thanks.
(SIGHS)
Ted, something big
has just happened
and you're the most
sensible person I know.
I need to talk
to you right now.
You know what,
it can wait.
No, go ahead.
I'm listening.
Okay, well,
the executive
producer from WNKW
happened to see our show
the other morning
and loved me.
(SIGHS) They offered me
the lead anchor job
starting next week.
Wow! That's great!
It is great.
But here's the catch.
WNKW is in...
(DRYER WHIRRING)
Helen, kill the dryer!
(WHIRRING STOPS)
Is in Chicago.
But you were
the fifth doppelganger.
How can you be you?
I called you, Barney.
We had a whole conversation.
Ah! Yes.
I know what happened.
See, people at work
have this very
strange expectation
that I, well, work.
(SCOFFS) I know. I know.
BARNEY: So to make
my colleagues think
I'm busting my hump
when I'm really out
humping busty chicks,
I decided to record
a special message.
(BARNEY ON VOICE MAIL)
What is up?
Gotta go, Big Chief.
How can it be
a recording?
You called me "Big Chief,"
my special workplace nickname.
Oh, buddy.
Hey, hey,
come on, Big Chief.
Don't. Just don't.
Why does this
have to happen now?
I mean, just when
things are going
so great with Don.
(SIGHING)
It's the never-ending
battle of my life.
Career versus romance.
(LAUGHS)
"Never-ending battle"?
Career's been trouncing
romance for years.
It's like the Globetrotters
versus the Generals.
Career's sinking
hook shots from
half court.
Romance is just
a bunch of slow,
white guys
who couldn't make it
in the Italian league.
Ted, I'm lost.
What should I do?
Okay, you seriously
need to talk to Don
about this.
I'm just too confused
to put this on Don.
I need to leave him
out of it until I
figure out what I want.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
And I'm sorry I can't
give you better advice
on this. The truth is,
it's impossible for me
to be objective about you
moving away.
Mmm.
Did you get
a manicure?
No, I didn't get a...
He sure did.
Flo!
Why are you brunette
and driving a cab?
Oh! That.
You know how it's
my dream to have sex
with at least one woman
from every country
on the planet?
Sure.
Wow. You're doing
surprisingly well
in the Baltics.
Mmm-hmm.
So I figured, what's the
quickest way to get around
the world in 180 lays?
Lease a cab and wait outside
the UN building for
hot foreign chicks.
BARNEY: It was
the perfect plan.
There was only one
small detail I didn't
take into account.
Chicks don't want
to bang cab drivers?
Chicks do not want
to bang cab drivers.
And I put a lot of
work into this one.
I can't believe this.
Now I gotta tell Lily
the fifth doppelganger
is a fake.
So, what does she care?
Lily decided that once
we spotted your doppelganger,
we'd start
trying to have kids.
Kids! No! Uh-uh!
The rule is, no kids
until you're at least 45.
Do you ever read my blog?
It's gotten a lot better.
I'm ready to be a dad,
you know?
But Lily needs some sign
from the universe.
And now
it could be years.
I'm sorry, buddy.
That'll be 37.50.
OLDER TED: So, that night,
Marshall went home to break
the bad news to Lily.
The universe has spoken.
Marshall Eriksen,
let's make a baby.
I...
Okay.
Hey.
(LAUGHING LOUDLY)
You... Hang on,
hang on, hang on.
I heard you were doing this,
so I wrote down some stuff.
"Hey, I'm planning
a white wedding.
"Tell me, Billy Idol,
is it a nice day for that?"
Some other
Billy Idol ones.
"If anyone's looking for
the real Slim Shady,
he's right here."
That one's only okay.
Robin, why aren't you
getting in on this?
Okay, first of all,
I'm getting tons
of compliments.
Second of all, tell him.
He's not getting
tons of compliments.
No, the other thing.
ROBIN: Oh.
I might move to
Chicago next week.
Hey, baby.
Mmm-hmm?
Not for nothing or nothing,
but we'd still be doing this
even if we hadn't seen
Doppelganger Barney, right?
Oh, but we did see him,
which means the universe,
in all its infinite wisdom,
is telling you to stick me
and stick me real good.
I can't. I can't,
in good conscience,
stick you.
(SIGHING)
I know what's
bothering you.
Really?
The cabbie just
didn't look enough
like Barney.
Well, that's
just not true.
No! Time out.
This is a group decision.
You can't just move
to Chicago, unless
we all say it's okay.
Barney, I think this
has to be Robin's...
Stay out of this, Brigitte
Nielsen or Dolph Lundgren
from Rocky IV.
We need Marshall and Lily.
That cabbie was, like,
a foot shorter than Barney.
He was the exact
same size.
And you know what?
I think he was Asian.
Yeah, that guy was like
a tiny, graying Asian man,
with a soul patch
and a potbelly.
Have you completely
forgotten what
Barney looks like?
You guys banging?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Why are you
in our bedroom?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Why are you
in our bedroom?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Why is Ellen DeGeneres
in our bedroom?
(ROBIN AND BARNEY GIGGLE)
Hey! This is working.
Wait a minute.
Candles, flowers.
Oh! I guess Marshall
"forgot" to tell you.
The fifth doppelganger
was me.
What, wait,
and you knew about this?
You lied to me?
By omission.
And it's only because
this whole "leave it to
the universe" thing of
yours is insane, Lily.
Baby, you knew I needed
to decide if we...
Lily, we need to be
in control of
our own destinies.
Guys! Guys!
We're forgetting what's
really important here.
Ted's blond.
(ALL GIGGLE)
Guys, I am
pulling this off.
Now, Robin has
something important
to tell you.
He's not
pulling it off.
No, the other thing.
He got a manicure.
The other thing.
I got a job offer
in Chicago.
Whoa!
That's why we all
came down here,
to try and talk Robin
out of making a huge...
Actually, I've already
made a decision.
(SIGHS) Guys,
I gotta take it.
I can't believe
we're losing Robin.
LILY: Guys, this might be
the depression talking,
but is Ted's hair
starting to look
kind of good?
MARSHALL: Thank God.
I thought I was
the only one.
BARNEY: He looks like
a freaking movie star.
And by the way,
this was a huge mistake.
I'm changing
my hair back.
Smart. Very smart.
Told you.
Not at all awesome.
Hey.
So, I just got off
the phone with Chicago.
Yes, I have made
a decision. Um...
I appreciate the offer,
but I can't take the job.
Thanks.
I'm staying.
Damn straight!
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, Lily.
Tell me something.
You saw actual Barney
driving that cab,
and you thought it was
a petite, potbellied
Asian man.
I know. Weird, right?
It's not weird.
It means you're not ready.
And I'm sorry that I tried
to rush things.
Our baby can wait for
the real Doppelganger Barney.
(SIGHS) Oh.
(IN PUPPET VOICE)
Hey, Moo-Moo.
Monty made you
thin crust pizza,
just the way you like it.
ROBIN: Mmm.
You okay?
Robin, you're not
gonna believe this.
I got offered
the lead anchor job
at WNKW in Chicago.
Oh!
Um...
What'd you say?
I said yes.
I've been waiting years
for a shot like this.
I was hoping
you'd understand.
Barney?
(IN ESTONIAN ACCENT)
I am simple street
performer from Estonia.
Who is this Barney?
Oh, he's just this guy
we know who has, like,
a really lame blog.
I hear it's getting better.
I mean, what is "blog"?
It's just
something that was cool,
like, eight years ago.
Still cool. Still sounds
pretty cool, man.
What's your name?
Kristof.
Kristof what?
Kristof Doppelganger.
Really?
Yeah.
You're gonna go
with the last name
"Doppelganger"?
That's my name, man.
Bro.
Robin, wait.
Please try
to understand.
Look, I gotta
get out of here.
Put yourself
in my shoes.
I mean, can you
imagine what it's like
to have the phone ring
and it's your dream job
on the other end?
Yes. I can.
Good luck in Chicago, Don.
Barney, why are you
doing this?
Wait a minute.
Could it be that
Barney Stinson actually
wants us to have kids?
Who is this Barney?
Take American chill pill.
Well, let me
tell you about him.
He talks
a big game about
how no one should
ever have kids before
they're at least 45.
I would be interested
in reading some of these
opinions in blog form.
But I think I know
what happened.
Yesterday, Barney thought
he had to say good-bye to
someone he truly loves.
And it got him thinking.
Maybe it wouldn't be
the worst thing
if a baby joined
our little group.
Babies can be cute.
Mmm.
And someday, he's gonna make
the best uncle in the world.
Because this Barney,
he's family to us.
Excuse me.
I heard you're
from Estonia. So am I.
Excuse me one moment.
Estonia would
close out the Baltics!
And I am street performer,
like you.
(GASPING)
Hey.
(CRYING)
Say yes to this.
Okay.
Can I move back in?
Yes.
But, Ted, am I just
the biggest idiot
in the world?
Look, think about
all of us five years ago,
when we first met you.
TED: Marshall and Lily
were just boyfriend
and girlfriend.
Now they're married
and thinking about kids.
And Barney? Barney was
never gonna commit to
anyone, ever.
And last year,
he fell in love.
And me, I was chasing
some girl I was
convinced was the one.
Now she's one of
my closest friends.
And you?
Five years ago,
you never would've chosen
love over your career.
But today, you did.
Looks like I'm
getting dumber.
No, just more courageous.
Look, we've all been
searching for the five
doppelgangers, right?
Mmm-hmm.
But eventually, over time,
we all become our own
doppelgangers.
You know, these completely
different people who just
happen to look like us.
Five Years Ago Robin?
That girl, she was
pretty great.
But Doppelganger Robin?
She's amazing.
We've, um...
We've had
a lot to drink.
I don't care.
(LAUGHING)
What?
Oh!
I forgot. I'm blond.
I have blond hair.
You're blond.
OLDER TED:
And that's the story
of how dyeing my hair blond
kept us from doing something
we both would have
regretted that night.
Kids, the universe is funny.
Oh, my God.
Yes! You're here!
I don't understand...
This is fantastic!
Baby, simmer.
Your husband's right here.
At least attempt to hide it.
Guys, follow me.
Guys, look!
The fifth doppelganger!
Uh, Lily?
That dude looks...
MARSHALL:
Guys, go with it.
OLDER TED: Kids,
you can ask the universe
for signs all you want.
It's uncanny.
Right?
Looks just like Barney.
Amazing.
It's like looking
in the mirror.
OLDER TED:
But ultimately, we only
see what we wanna see,
when we're
ready to see it.
So, does this mean...
Marshall Eriksen,
put a baby in my belly.
(LIFESIZE PLAYING)
* All for love we become
* Larger than lifesize,
wondersome *
* Great in the eyes
of someone *