OLDER TED: Kids, your
Aunt Robin had only been
dating Don a short while,
when one evening,
out of nowhere...
Robin?
Hmm.
Do you wanna move in?
(STUTTERING) Well,
it's kind of soon, but,
sure, I would
consider moving in here.
Just let me think about it.
No, I meant do you wanna
move in on the couch so
I could sit down?
Yeah. That's
what I meant, too.
Like I said, just
let me think about it.
Okay.
Yeah. I'm okay with that.
But now that
you mentioned it,
do you wanna move in?
So, what did you say?
I'm considering it.
You're considering it?
Yeah.
You barely know him.
Plus, the guy's a loser
with a dead-end job.
We have the
same job, Barney.
And we couldn't be
prouder of you, angel.
Ugh.
Well, sweetie,
this does seem
kind of fast.
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
I think you
should move in with him.
You do?
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean,
I see how happy you are.
And as much as I
love you as a roommate,
I want you to do
what's right for you.
Oh!
Are you
trying to kick me out
because of the milk thing?
It's really annoying.
(SHOUTING) Robin!
No. I have a system.
I put the empty
carton back in the fridge
to remind us to buy milk.
Okay, why don't you leave
a full carton to remind us
we don't have to buy milk?
All right, all right.
As your ex, before
you jump into anything,
I need to meet this guy.
I think it's kind of weird
that I haven't met him yet.
Totally weird.
It's almost like someone
carefully orchestrated
it that way on purpose.
Fine. But
you have to promise to
be on your best behavior.
I promise.
So, I'm banging
this Portuguese
contortionist
and I swear,
she is so flexible,
at one point
she was on top of
me and underneath me.
Up top and down low!
One and two, bang!
Who needs?
I'm good. I'm good.
And that would be Barney.
He means well.
Well, actually,
I'm not sure that's true.
I think he's awesome.
But I feel bad for any woman
with the kind of low
self-esteem
who would actually
date a guy like that.
OLDER TED: And that's
when I realized Robin never
told Don she had dated Barney.
I like you, Don.
We both love a good Scotch.
We both enjoy my
compelling stories.
Yeah.
And we both dated Robin.
OLDER TED:
Now he knew.
So, Barney's your ex and
you still hang out with him?
I got to say I'm a little
uncomfortable with that.
Oh, look, don't be.
It's like we never dated.
Long story short, this
exchange student's
arms gave out,
and we both fell,
ass over sex swing.
Seriously,
I have not been
able to find a girl
who can do that
position since Robin.
Hey, Lily! Marshall!
How was
your weekend away,
or any other topic?
Awful.
Terrible.
Twin beds?
We can't sleep
in separate beds.
We should go complain.
Yeah, you're right. I'm gonna
march down there and demand
another room.
Yeah, I'll go with you
in just a sec.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAID: Housekeeping.
Could you come back later?
We're taking a little catnap.
MAID: It's time to check out.
We slept for 18 hours.
We missed four
pre-paid meals.
I lost 11 pounds.
Hey, Ted, do you think
it's weird that Robin is
still friends with Barney?
I think it's weird
that we're all still
friends with Barney.
I just don't know
how I feel about
her hanging out
with one of her
exes all the time.
OLDER TED:
And that's when I realized
Robin had failed to tell Don
about another one of
her exes, me.
No, hanging out
with one ex is fine.
Even two, I'd give a pass.
Hell, two might be
even better than one,
for some reason.
Yeah, but if you
were dating someone
and he hung out with one
of his exes all the time...
Oh, wait, I'm sorry. "He"?
Yeah, and he was friends
with one of his exes...
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, dude, dude,
hold on.
Do you think I'm gay?
Well, yeah.
Why would you assume that?
Hey.
Hey, Ted, your
calligraphy teacher called.
And? And?
Your ink is in.
Yes!
Hey, guys,
I just wanna make sure
Project Runway is recording.
Did the Jets
get new costumes?
Well, I guess
we won't be having
creme brulee tonight.
My browning torch is broken.
You know,
when I heard your
roommate was a single guy,
I was a little jealous.
But now that I know
he's gay, I'm okay.
Oh, Ted's not...
But we still got
homemade lady fingers
and piping hot Darjeeling.
Awesome. Thank you.
Ted's not what?
Ted's not
gonna be around a lot.
He's following Cher on tour.
Okay, don't get me wrong,
Cher puts on a hell of
a show.
But I am not gay.
Hey, Lily, be honest.
Is it weird that
Robin hangs out with one
of her exes all the time?
Well, Ted and Robin
broke up years ago.
It's a non-issue.
Ted and Robin?
Not seeming so gay now,
am I, Donny?
Appletini for
the gentleman.
Thank you.
You dated Ted, too?
Robin, of the four people
you consider your best
friends in New York,
you've slept
with 50% of them.
Don, they're just my friends.
Yeah, but they're
also your exes.
And you live
with one of them.
Look, I'm sorry, I got to...
I got to think about all this.
LILY: (SIGHING) Mmm.
Mmm.
MARSHALL: My God,
she's a thousand degrees!
It's like putting my
leg against a tailpipe.
LILY: Ow! His toenails
are like daggers.
MARSHALL:
I'd love a sandwich,
but no eating in bed.
Stupid rule.
We have ants one time.
LILY: Great, and now
he's falling asleep.
Cue the river of drool.
(GRUNTS)
MARSHALL:
My knee itches.
Just one little scratch.
Marshall!
I think we should
get separate beds.
Yes! A mini fridge
and separate beds.
Deal!
Don.
Hi.
I came to apologize to
all of you. I overreacted.
Well, we owe you
an apology, too, Don.
We said some
pretty hurtful things.
No, you didn't.
Right, right,
that was after you left.
I'm sorry I didn't
tell you the truth
in the first place.
No, I acted
like a total drama queen.
That's not offensive, right?
Still not gay.
Sorry.
So, look, the point
is you both are clearly
very important to Robin.
So, why don't
we all have dinner
tomorrow night at my place?
Oh, that's great.
Looking forward to it, buddy.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
DON: You want to go?
Yeah.
See you guys.
Bye.
Ted?
Yeah?
I must have Robin back.
You're kidding, right?
No.
I don't know what it is,
but I want Robin back.
I know what it is.
You're like a little kid
who throws a toy away
and then wants it back
the second another kid
starts playing with it.
Well, maybe I wasn't
done playing with it.
Maybe I just set it down
'cause I wanted to play with
some other stuff for a second!
Okay.
You're ready.
Ready for what?
To read the letter.
OLDER TED:
Kids, the letter was
a device I'd invented
to remind myself why
I'd broken up with somebody.
I'd been doing it for years.
"Dear Future Ted,
never get back
with Karen
"because she's
a pretentious snob.
"Oh, also,
she cheated on you.
"I'm sorry you had
to find out this way.
(CHUCKLES)
"See, we're already
laughing about it."
"Dear Future Ted,
stay away from Natalie,
"or any girl who can
pin you to the ground
"and beat you senseless
in front of a cheering crowd.
"P.S. Please
consult a therapist
"about why that turned you on
a little bit."
"Dear Relationship Genius,
"Stella left
you at the altar.
"You may never love again
and will probably die alone."
Huh!
It doesn't look so sad
written in calligraphy.
OLDER TED:
So, when Barney and Robin
broke up the previous fall...
Dating Robin
was a huge mistake.
Write that down.
What?
Write yourself a letter.
That way, when you
miss Robin, and you will,
you can
remind yourself
why you broke up.
Gladly.
"Dear Future Barney..."
Ooh!
This ink is cool.
Right? Right?
"You and Robin..."
"Were a terrible couple.
"It just didn't work.
Sure, you'll always
love Robin,
"but remember other women?
"More importantly,
remember other boobs?
"And all
the cool stuff
you can do with boobs?
"Nuzzle, juggle, honka-honka.
"I guess I'm just
a hopeless romantic."
Then there's
just a bunch of
drawings of boobs.
You get it now?
Yeah, I get it.
I definitely want her back.
(SIGHS)
I don't think human beings
were ever meant to sleep
in the same bed.
Somehow sex and sleep
got all jumbled together,
but they're two
different things.
I know.
I mean, I love you,
but I want this new bed
to be a sanctuary for
sleep and sleep alone.
Me, too. And some
light snacking,
but that's it.
Hey, you know
what we should get?
We should get a third bed
just for sex.
Yes! A sex bed!
A dirty, dirty sex bed!
It's genius. That way
each bed would have
a specific purpose.
Exactly. We'll have
two sleep beds, a sex bed,
and I'm thinking
a bean bag chair,
just for
special birthday stuff.
Baby, did we just
revolutionize modern marriage?
Damn straight!
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Hey!
Hey, guys.
Hey, Don.
I hope you like sushi.
How cool is it
that Don makes sushi?
He learned while on
assignment in Japan.
Ringworm-ilicious.
Barney, be nice.
You only want her
'cause you can't have her.
It's like if I said
you can sit anywhere
in this room
except that chair.
Are you so petty that...
My chair! My chair!
Oh, spicy tuna with
jalapeno! My favorite!
Mine, too.
I love spicy food.
The hotter the better.
I love
spicy stuff, too, guy.
Probably more than you do.
Check it.
Don't...
Super mild.
I'm not feeling it.
Hey, Lily,
you won't believe it,
it's the craziest thing.
Don has twin beds, too.
Oh, my God!
We just got twin beds.
Oh, Oh. Great, great.
Well, wait, that "great"
didn't sound so great.
Well, my ex-wife and I
thought they'd be
a good idea,
but we just started
to drift apart. So...
Yeah, but
I bet you didn't have
another bed just for sex.
No, but she did at her
personal trainer's house.
This chili is like
an ice cube in my mouth.
I will say this, though.
I'm gonna
get a king-size bed if
Robin decides to move in.
Oh, I'd like that.
If I move in.
If you move in.
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, Tokyo Don,
you ever do this
back in Japan?
Wasabi!
I wouldn't, Barney, no.
Hey. Oh, my God, Barney?
(EXCLAIMS)
Awesome!
Give him some milk!
Spit it out, Barney!
Spit it out!
Oh, we're out of milk.
But thanks for
the reminder, Robin.
(EXCLAIMING)
ROBIN: Oh, sweet.
Well, I hope you're happy.
Hey, I stand by what I did.
It was bold and romantic.
You soiled yourself
from both ends of your body.
Oh, come on!
You have done tons of
stupid stuff to impress Robin.
Yeah, I did,
but I don't anymore,
'cause I'm over her.
Just like you are.
You are not over her.
You want her back
just as much as I do.
You just won't
let yourself go there.
That is ridiculous.
And I'll tell you why.
"For my biographer"?
Just... Just focus
on the letter, okay?
"Dear Ted, Robin is
the perfect girl for you.
"But she doesn't wanna be
in a serious relationship.
"You need someone
who wants to settle down,
"so until Robin's
ready for that next
step, she's not your girl.
"Still, I'll always remember
stealing her the blue
French horn,
"our first kiss,
"the look in her eye
when she told me she
loved me."
Damn it.
Now I want her back.
OLDER TED: So, that night,
your Uncle Barney and I sat down
to have a calm,
rational discussion,
about who
deserved Robin more.
No!
I stole her
a blue French horn!
I dated her for a year!
I wanted her to be
the mother of my children
and spend eternity
in her arms.
See, I wanna
have sex with her
at least one more time!
She is mine!
She's not yours!
And she's not mine, either.
She's Don's.
You're right.
We got to get
rid of that guy.
Yeah.
You know, figuratively.
Of course.
Or literally.
Oh, my God, Ted,
this is how it starts!
This is how it starts!
I'm scared, Teddy,
I'm scared, Teddy!
(SHUSHING)
Two guys talking.
Just two guys talking.
Okay. Okay.
Marshall, I'm worried.
I don't wanna get divorced.
Oh, baby.
Honey, that's Don.
That's not us.
Our new sleeping arrangement
is only gonna bring us
closer together.
Now get out of my bed.
Can we at least
push them together?
Sure.
Oh, you meant the beds.
No, I don't wanna do that.
Why not?
Baby, I love you
more than life itself.
But you're
a million degrees.
Honestly, I'm surprised
your hourly pee breaks
aren't just steam.
Well, you're no
picnic in bed, either.
Oh, except for
the food and the ants.
But, well,
I still wanna
be next to you.
Why? So you can kick
me and slap me all night?
I swear to God,
the second you
fall asleep,
it's like you
grow extra limbs.
It's like spooning
with a Hindu deity,
Ganesh!
Wanna push them together?
You still talking
about the beds?
Nope.
Get over here.
Robin Stinson!
Robin Mosby!
Ted Scherbatsky!
I'll take her name.
I don't care.
Okay. Wait.
How about this?
We share her.
I'll take her until she's 40,
and then you can have her
after that.
Okay, who
are we kidding?
She's with Don now.
We just have to accept that,
and move on.
You're right.
I'm gonna go to the...
I'm gonna go to the bathroom,
and then I'll skedaddle.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Hey, Robin,
it's Barn Door.
Guess what? I'm open.
(CELL PHONE BEEPING)
Hey, Barn Door, hang on.
I'm getting another call.
Hello?
Hey, Robin,
it's Teddy Bear.
Need a little honey?
(GROWLING)
No. Ted, hang on.
Okay.
Hey, Barney,
I'm gonna have
to call you back.
Ted's on the other line,
and I think he's in trouble.
Ted's calling you?
He's in trouble,
all right!
Ted, what's up?
You have pretty hair.
That's what's up.
And down your back.
(GROWLING SUGGESTIVELY)
(SCREAMING)
Wow. We almost let
that get out of control.
Agreed.
I'm gonna get out of here
before we do something
we regret.
Robin! Robin, I love you!
You son of a bitch!
Robin!
Robin, I brought you
the blue French horn!
I brought you
Robin, Ted's just
holding it for me.
Sorry, buddy, all's fair.
Oh, God. Guys,
what are you doing?
Robin, I wanna win you back!
Hey, guys.
Why don't you
come upstairs?
Right.
All right, Don!
Let's settle this.
You, me and Ted!
Yeah! A three-way.
Look, guys,
Robin and I have
to go do our show,
so why don't you have a seat
on the couch, watch some
television,
and we'll
talk about this
when we get back, okay?
Wow, you give up easy.
Game, set, match.
Winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
Where's...
Where's this TV
you've been bragging about?
It's right here.
(BOTH SIGH)
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Good night, boys.
Good night.
Night, night, Papa.
That was nice.
Yeah.
Well, she gots to go.
What?
Oh, I'm sorry.
That was a blast.
And you're great.
But I have to
be up early, so...
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Well, you're
just kicking me out?
You knew what this was.
Lily, Lily, wait.
Don't forget your
sweatshirt. Nice try.
Teddy Bear! Barn Door!
Papa?
Rise and shine, jackasses!
So, do you guys remember
anything from last night?
Yeah.
Boy, was Ted drunk.
Embarrassing.
I'm really sorry.
We both are.
We were drunk and stupid.
But we're gonna
do anything we can
to make sure that Don
feels a part of the group.
Don's not gonna be
a part of the group.
And neither am I.
At least for a while.
Guys, this thing
with Don is real.
And I wanna see where it goes.
And I'll never
be able to do that
if I keep hanging out
with my ex-boyfriends
all the time.
It just won't work.
I'm moving in with Don.
* It should be boredom by now
* I know the tricks
So, what's going on
with Robin?
You were right.
She was just mad.
It's been four days,
she hasn't said another
word about moving out.
But listen, we can never
pull crap like that
ever again.
Agreed. In fact, I even
wrote myself another letter.
"Dear Future Barney,
"you think you want Robin
back again, but you
really don't.
"Let her go.
Sincerely, Past Barney."
Let me see that.
Hey, hey, give it to me.
All right, all right,
"P.S. That top part
was just for Ted.
"Did he buy it? Good.
"Now get back
together with Robin.
"But don't mention your plan
to Ted,
"'cause he'll just
screw it up again."
And then there's
more drawings of boobs.
Okay, okay.
In my defense,
how great are boobs?
They're pretty great.
So?
(EXCLAIMS)
(SHOUTING) Robin!
* Just like a heavy drinker
* I go for it every time
* Hook, line and sinker