OLDER TED:
Kids, as long as I'd
known your Uncle Barney,
he'd always
had some pretty strong
opinions on relationships.
Your girlfriend?
She's your "girlfriend"?
She's a girl, and a friend?
(LAUGHING) How is...
Do not humanize
the enemy, Ted.
But nice to meet you,
Barney Stinson.
OLDER TED: And yet,
in the fall of 2009,
he was the one
with the girlfriend.
Go ahead, open it.
Open it, open it,
open it, open it!
It's my porn collection!
Just kidding.
That would be weird.
It's your porn collection.
It's my porn collection!
I'm giving you my porn.
Now that things
are so great with Robin,
I don't need it anymore.
Wow. You are voluntarily
giving up your porn.
You really are serious.
Well, that's obvious.
What does that mean?
Oh, nothing.
It's just, you know,
you got relationship gut.
What? No, I do not
got "relationship gut."
That is ridiculous.
It's no big deal. I mean,
once you're dating someone,
it's natural to let things
go a little bit. Trust me.
We've been there.
Yeah. Boy, did I
pudge out for a while.
Well, we should get going.
Good-bye, my sweet,
beloved friends, who
have always been there for me.
You'll be missed.
He's talking to the porn.
Oh.
MARSHALL AND LILY: Bye, Robin.
TED: See you, Robs.
(LAUGHING)
Look at these videos.
Space Orgy. Horny
Co-Ed Surprise Party 23.
You'd think after
the first 22 parties,
the coeds wouldn't
be surprised anymore.
So, we can
get rid of these for you.
No. No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
It's not a problem.
I'll take care of them.
Are you sure?
I mean, no biggie.
We can just swing by
the back alley and drop
the box in the Dumpster.
I see six of the words you
just said on this video label.
Seriously,
it's not a big deal.
I will take care of it.
No. 'Cause I... I mean, we...
Leave them!
Okay.
You know,
in a way, it's sad, right?
I mean, Barney's
giving up his porn.
He's got
relationship gut.
They eat at the
same diner every night.
It's like the end
of Barney Stinson
as we know him.
Yeah, well, so what?
They're happy...
Yeah, well,
we gotta go. Later.
(WHISPERING)
So, what'd you get?
I got Squat.
What are you...
I thought I saw you take one?
Yeah, I did.
It's called Squat.
"Archisexture."
That is not
how you spell
"Buckminster Fuller."
OLDER TED:
Kids, pornography is bad.
And so, I was
getting rid of that vile
pornography right away...
I am getting rid of this
vile pornography right away.
OLDER TED:
...when something
terrible happened.
Oh, no.
WOMAN: (IN HUSKY VOICE)
Archisexture...
Hello, Ted.
If you're
watching this tape, and
I knew you'd pick this one,
then you are now in
possession of my porn.
This can only mean
one of two things,
either I'm dead,
or I'm in
a committed relationship.
If I'm dead,
I want you to
honor my memory
by taking my body
to The Hamptons
and recreating
Weekend at Bernie's.
I wanna dance,
I wanna have
sex with a girl
and I wanna go fishing.
If, on the other hand,
I'm in a committed
relationship,
then, as your best friend,
I have only one request.
Please, for the love of God,
get me out of it!
I might look happy,
but don't believe it.
Barney Stinson is
meant to be single.
So, please,
if you value my
best friendship...
That's right, Marshall,
I'm his best friend.
How does that feel?
Then get me out of this.
And, finally, since you
were expecting some porn.
No, no, no, baby.
Don't worry.
The flashing green
light means it's off.
Are we sure
he was finished talking?
Look, there's no reason
we should take this
seriously, right?
Of course not.
This is an old tape.
Barney is happy with Robin.
OLDER TED: But over
the next couple of weeks,
I started to notice things.
Barney and Robin stopped
having crazy adventures.
So, what'd you
guys do last night?
I wanted to
go to a concert.
He wanted to
go to a party.
Obviously, we couldn't do
what just one of us wanted,
so we just stayed in,
watched a movie on cable.
It was Legen... Wait for it.
...ds of the Fall.
Legends of the Fall!
It was okay.
OLDER TED:
Barney stopped being himself.
Hey, Barney.
I'm chatting up
this girl over there.
I could use a little
help landing the plane.
Sorry, Ted,
I'm my own wingman tonight.
(LAUGHING)
OLDER TED:
And Robin got annoyed
at everything he said.
So, how are you two?
Great.
Yeah.
Relationships are the best.
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
The sharing,
the compromise.
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
The monogamy,
can't beat it.
Catchphrase, yes.
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
OLDER TED:
But the worse they got...
I'm full, sweetie.
OLDER TED:
...the more they kept
saying things were great.
Now the truth is,
Barney and Robin
only let themselves go
a little bit.
But I swear,
after a few more weeks,
to us, they seemed like this.
I'll be there,
(SNIFFS) in a minute.
(SIGHS)
Hey.
They're killing each other!
They love each other.
Barney and Robin love
each other,
but they're not
Barney and Robin anymore.
They're the fat guy
and the old lady.
My favorite
'70s detective show.
Look, it's so clear.
Barney's been overeating
because he hates being
tied down like this.
And Robin's stressing out
because she hates what
Barney's turned into.
No. They're a perfect match.
Well, maybe
that's the problem.
I mean, maybe
they're too similar.
It must be tough having
two alpha dogs in one
relationship.
We have
two alpha dogs
in our relationship.
Sure we do, sweetie.
If they're not happy,
why don't they just
break up?
Because they're too stubborn.
Neither one of them
wants to be the first
to admit that they want out.
They're playing
relationship chicken.
I think Barney ate
the relationship chicken.
(LAUGHING)
Ted, it's just a rough patch.
It takes time
getting used to
being with someone else.
And they're both...
What's the nice
word for selfish?
Independent.
Independent. Every
relationship goes
through this.
It's true.
I have
this astronaut friend,
totally loved his fiancée.
And then, the day before
his mission, she caught him
with, like,
four other chicks,
a couple of dudes.
Things got really tense.
Finally, she ended up
sneaking out of the
space shuttle...
Are you talking
about Space Orgy?
Yes, I am.
Ted, it's just a rough patch.
Just let things run
their course.
She's right.
TED: But...
Two-to-one, Ted.
Leave them alone.
OLDER TED:
So I did leave them alone.
But that weekend...
Mmm.
Have you
noticed how beef ribs
used to always be disgusting,
and then recently they found
a way to make them really
delicious instead?
Okay, Barney.
I'm gonna go ahead
and ask you this head on.
Are you happy with Robin?
Are you kidding?
How could I not be
happy with Robin?
It's Robin!
So are you happy?
I can't believe
you'd even ask me that.
I mean, yes,
we fight all the time,
but, you know what they
say about relationships.
"Every moment's a battle."
So are you happy?
And you know what
goes hand-in-hand
with fighting,
the make-up sex,
which is different
when you're in a loving,
long-term relationship.
Heads, we have sex.
Tails, we order
a whole pizza and
just lay here moaning.
Oh, great.
Let the coin decide.
(SIGHS)
Which was pizza again?
Tails.
It was tails.
Sex. Am I right?
Thank God that's mostly over.
(BURPS)
I'm still hungry. You hungry?
We have to break them up.
You're right.
Barney and Robin
are miserable together,
but they're too
stubborn to admit it.
So, we have to
get them to break up.
How do we do that?
We unleash the Kraken.
OLDER TED: Kids, as you know,
earlier that year,
I'd learned that
Lily had broken up not one,
not two, but seven of my
past relationships.
Forget it.
I'm retired.
I'm out of the game.
But nobody's
better than you.
I'm telling you.
I swore off that racket.
I've gone legit.
I'm a matchmaker now.
Set me up with someone.
Whoa! I'm just starting out.
Listen, you've gotta
break them up.
This relationship is
killing them.
I know it is, but
I've learned my lesson.
No more interfering.
Let things run their course.
It's two-to-one.
Yes, but the one is me.
All right, we don't need her.
We can break them up on
our own.
How?
Okay, remember when
Robin and I were dating?
What was the one big thing
that really freaked her out?
No. No. No. No. No. Ted,
you cannot do this to me.
No! No. No. No.
What are you
talking about?
This. This is
what I'm talking about.
What is this doing
in my champagne?
If we make Robin think
for even a second that
Barney is proposing,
she'll lose it,
and they'll break up.
That's crazy.
Why don't we just, like,
lead Barney into temptation?
We'll find some hot
woman to hit on him.
Okay, the ring thing.
Stakeout van.
What?
We should have
gotten a stakeout van.
We could have ordered pizza,
and looked through big
binoculars
and said, "This ain't
what I signed up for."
Stuff like that.
TED: Shh...
Here comes the waiter.
Please, shut up!
What?
I thought you
said something. Sorry.
Is that an engagement ring?
Are you?
Oh, no. No.
That's not me. They must've
delivered it to the
wrong table.
Could you imagine,
us getting married?
(LAUGHING)
Well, we are
committed to
each other.
Most of your stuff is
already at my apartment.
Might make
taxes easier.
Speed up your citizenship.
"Scherbatsky" is
so hard to spell.
My mom would be so happy.
(SIGHING) I guess so.
No reason not to.
We're getting married!
Not so loud. Geez!
What did you do?
I am furious right now.
This is so wrong!
Lily, will you be
my maid of honor?
Oh, my God.
I would love to.
Are you out of your mind?
You knew they were playing
relationship chicken, and
what did you do?
You put an engagement ring
in front of them.
Okay.
That's it.
I'm taking over.
I'm coming
out of retirement
for one last breakup.
(EXCLAIMING) Yes!
All right.
How are we
gonna do it?
These guys are in so deep
just one fight ain't
gonna do it.
We need to reignite the four
biggest fights they've
ever been in,
all at once.
Number one,
the battle of
the dirty dishes.
(INAUDIBLE)
Number two,
the ex-girlfriend conflict.
Hey, don't you know
that girl over there?
No. I don't think so.
No, in fact,
I have definitely...
Hey, it's Meg.
Well, I am certainly not
comparing you two in my
mind right now.
Whoops. Hey,
will you get that for me?
Really?
Please?
Why do you keep doing this?
You're embarrassing me
in public.
You're constantly
putting me in these positions.
Number three,
the Star Wars altercation.
Isn't it time you got
rid of your stupid doll?
It's not a doll.
It's a Stormtrooper.
Uh... He's wearing a diaper.
It's not
a diaper, Robin.
It's protective armor.
Stormtrooper,
more like Stormpooper.
Stop it!
(IMITATING FARTING) Whoa! Oh!
It sounds
like your Stormpooper
here needs a changing.
Okay, you know what,
I'm sick of it.
I'm sick of your jokes.
I didn't say anything.
Your jokes about the magic...
I can't joke?
And of course, the biggie,
the Canadian-American war.
Thank God that song's over.
Who the hell was that old
lady singing?
Okay, you know
that Neil Young is
my favorite musician.
Right. Now was
that the same old lady
who played
Archie Bunker's wife
in All in the Family,
or just a sound-alike?
Neil Young is
a Canadian treasure.
Do not make fun of Neil Young.
Robin, I would
never make fun
of a defenseless, old lady
with vocal cord paralysis.
Here we go.
Ever.
In public? Really?
Yeah, in public.
I'll go there.
We're gonna have
a fight in public?
It's nothing
to be mad about.
I got it.
We e-mail them pictures
reminding them of
each of these fights.
You child.
Here's how it goes down.
They're at the diner.
First, rekindling the
Canadian-American debate,
Ontario native Alan Thicke
stops by the table.
BOTH: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Alan Thicke?
Oh! Right, Robin knew him
back when she was a singer.
Yeah, and they
still keep in touch.
I already got his
number off her phone.
Seriously, amateurs.
LILY:
So Alan Thicke restarts
the Canada-US fight.
Right at that moment,
Crazy Meg shows up.
Then, a Stormtrooper
happens to walk by
the window.
And just
when they can't
take anything more,
a busboy walks by
with a tray full of what?
Dirty dishes.
(INAUDIBLE)
Lily, this is
your masterpiece.
We're getting
a stakeout van!
A station wagon? Really?
You rented a station wagon?
Yeah, a van cost,
like, 25 bucks more.
A station wagon. (SCOFFS)
LOST IN SPACE ROBOT:
Greetings, Will Robinson!
Where's the birthday boy
or girl?
Hey, climb on in.
What the hell is this?
They didn't have
any Stormtroopers,
so I had to get
a different robot.
This will still work.
Different robot?
Stormtroopers aren't robots.
Of course they're robots.
(ROBOT VOICE)
"Must kill Luke Skywalker."
Nobody says
that in Star Wars.
Really lousy
robot voice, honey.
Someone ordered
an extra-large sausage.
Hey, one of
Barney's videos
starts off just like that.
Hey, guys,
Barney's ordering
five of something.
I don't know if
it's gonna fit in here.
Okay. Now you're
just quoting the video.
Still ordering.
Waiter's taking
out a second pad.
Yeah, okay, well,
we need it in here.
We're on a stakeout.
Shouldn't you be in a van?
A van costs more.
Thank you.
Score me a slice,
Will Robinson.
No, no, no. You get
a stain on that costume,
they're gonna charge us.
Dude, will you
just chill about money.
Yeah, let the Stormtrooper
have a slice.
Yeah. It's not a Stormtrooper.
It's not a Stormtrooper.
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
Hi, Lily.
Sorry I'm late.
I was looking for a van.
Thank you.
$25.
So, should I go
say hi to Robin?
Not yet. Get in the car.
Okay, so wait, wait, wait.
When they blew up the
Death Star,
knowing full well
there were thousands
of Stormtroopers on it,
those were people?
Well, it was called
the Death Star, baby.
They knew what
they were getting into.
Look, I don't wanna play
the "I'm Alan Thicke" card,
but I really do have
a dinner to get to, so...
Someone has gotta
take this sausage.
Okay, were you in that video?
Were you the guy
with the farmer tan?
Jonesing for some za,
Will Robinson.
Come on,
I'm Alan Thicke!
This ain't what
I signed up for.
Hey, that's my...
Okay, you know what,
everyone stop!
Alan Thicke, shut up!
Marshall, it's
a station wagon, get over it!
Ted, stop talking about porn!
And for the
love of God, somebody get
the Stormtrooper some pizza!
It's not a Stormtrooper.
Crap!
They see us.
LOST IN SPACE ROBOT:
Danger! Danger!
(WHISPERING) Are
you sure they saw us?
Yes.
Hey!
Can I go talk to Barney now?
I'm so excited.
Do you really think
he's gonna propose to me?
Oh, honey.
Forget it, Crazy Meg.
We've been made.
If we try anything now,
they're gonna know it's us.
I think we should all
just go home.
No! This is my masterpiece.
So what if they saw us?
It'll still work.
Stop it!
We'll think of
something else.
Let me repeat,
I am Alan Thicke.
(GASPS) You're Alan Thicke?
No.
Alan Thicke, you're up.
Get on out there.
OLDER TED: And so, Lily
followed through with
her plan.
First, Alan Thicke,
followed by Crazy Meg,
then the robot
and, finally,
the dirty dishes.
But by the end of it...
They're kissing.
They shouldn't be kissing.
Why isn't this working?
Because they're in love.
It really was
just a rough patch.
What the hell am I doing?
This whole thing
was a mistake.
So, any of you
dudes wanna get high?
I never thought I'd
be saying this tonight,
but to Barney and Robin,
the happy couple.
OLDER TED: That was the moment
we learned that relationships
take hard work,
but eventually,
everything will work out.
Hey.
Where's Barney?
Uh... We broke up.
OLDER TED: And that was
the moment we unlearned
that other lesson
we had just learned
a few seconds earlier.
You see,
earlier that night,
when Lily thought Barney
and Robin had spotted her,
this is what
they really saw.
Why do that fat guy
and old lady keep...
Oh, my God. That's us.
Look at us. Did we
always look this awful?
Robin, I'm not happy.
I mean, I wish I was.
Nothing would
make me happier
than being happy,
but I'm not.
But what are
we doing wrong?
We love each other.
I mean, if this
doesn't work, what will?
We're so similar.
We both like scotch.
We're both awesome.
You know, maybe that's it.
Maybe there's just too
much awesome here.
Exactly. Two awesomes
cancel each other out.
I'm tired of
being canceled out.
Me, too.
Are we breaking up?
I think so.
Aw, crap.
Now comes the next part,
the part where you and I
can't go back to being
friends.
Well, maybe
this isn't a breakup.
Maybe this
is two friends
getting back together.
ALAN: Robin?
Hi.
It's always so great
to see a fellow hoser.
Oh. Yes.
Hi. Good news. I forgive you
for the whole restraining
order thing.
Uh, hi.
ROBIN: Was that
a Stormtrooper?
That's not a...
You wanna
get outta here?
Yeah.
Excuse me.
See you, guys.
Okay.
See you, Alan.
So, you still
on 73rd Street?
How do you know that?
Getting back together
as friends. I like that.
One more for the road?
And, I mean, who knows,
maybe when, like,
you turn 40, if you
haven't found anyone...
I already have
that deal with Ted.
Oh! Right. Stupid.
Well, maybe when you turn 39,
if you haven't found anyone...
(LAUGHING)
OLDER TED: It turns out
that they really did
just need to let
things run their course.
So, how's Barney doing?
He's okay, I think.
It might be a while before
he fully recovers, but...
Mmm.
Did you guys
just feel a chill?
Yeah.
Daddy's home.
Well, Robin,
I'm glad we could catch up.
Yeah. Let's
do it again soon.
I love that you
guys are still friends
so long after you
did that music video.
Yeah.
The music...
The Sandcastles video.
Yes, yes. We did that
together, too.
What do you mean "too"?
Well, we had this failed
Canadian TV variety show.
That was so embarrassing.
Imagine what would happen
if anybody ever got their
hands on that?
Ooh! You.
(SIGHING)