OLDER TED: Kids,
back in 2009,
your Aunt Robin
was the host
of a morning show
for local New York cable.
And it was on pretty early.
How early?
(LOUD SNORING)
ROBIN: Mike? Wake up.
(GRUNTING)
OLDER TED: But then,
everything changed.
Coming up next...
Hey.
See my show?
Aw, I meant to watch it.
I just got
so busy with the whole
being-sound-asleep thing.
It took all night,
eight hours down
the drain.
It's fine.
But get this.
After the broadcast...
Hi. Are you Robin?
Yeah.
I'm Don,
your new co-host.
OLDER TED: Don was Don Frank,
a seasoned veteran of no fewer
than 38 local
morning news teams
from all over the country.
The guy was
an industry legend.
Oh!
Wow! You are so
going to hit that.
No! I just
think we're going to be
great together on the air.
And on the sofa and on the
bed and on the coffee table.
All right, all right.
I'm gonna go up on the roof
and stand there by myself
for five minutes.
Have fun.
OLDER TED: And that's
exactly what she did.
She just stood there.
All right, kids,
I'm gonna level with you.
That's not
what she did.
Here's what she did.
All right, all right.
(GRUNTING) I'm going
to go have a cigarette.
What?
OLDER TED:
I promised her
I'd never tell you this,
but once upon a time, your
Aunt Robin did enjoy the
occasional cigarette,
and occasionally that
occasional cigarette was
more than just occasional.
I just left something
like this in my apartment.
Robin, come on,
take it to the roof.
We said
no smoking in
the apartment
after you torched the
throw rug doing push-ups.
All right,
all right,
all right.
Yeah, Robin. I mean, God,
not only is that
a filthy habit,
but also,
can I bum one?
Sure.
What?
OLDER TED: Kids, your
Uncle Marshall definitely
doesn't want you to know this,
but he also
smoked off and on.
It all started
when he was 13,
on a camping
trip in Minnesota.
Come on,
Marshall, let's celebrate.
It's summer vacation.
Okay, but just one.
This is my first
and last cigarette ever.
OLDER TED: And that
was the first of many,
many last cigarettes ever.
That's it.
I am done, I am out.
Last... Cigarette... Ev-arr!
OLDER TED:
So, by that point,
I'd heard it all before.
Last cigarette ever.
What are you doing?
You haven't smoked
in six months.
Is this about the McRib?
It's gone, dude. Let it go.
I'm worried about work, okay?
They just hired a new
head of the legal department,
and he's going to
be letting people go.
So that's why
you're worried?
The new head of the legal
department is Arthur Hobbs.
As in Artillery Arthur?
As in your former boss?
OLDER TED:
Arthur Hobbs was
the meanest boss
Marshall or anyone
else had ever had.
The last time
Marshall worked for
him, it ended like this.
I quit!
Yikes. So, does he
hold it against you?
Worse.
I'm sorry,
who are you?
I'm Marshall Eriksen.
Um, we had a fairly
intense screaming match.
No.
Wherein I suggested
that you take your head
and store it
within yourself
in a fashion that,
well, while space-saving
might limit its
exposure to sunshine.
Well, that describes
95% of my employees
and everyone in my family,
except for my dog.
He's such a good boy.
Well, I'll see you later,
Randall Wilkerson.
Marshall Eriksen.
Gary Dinkersfield, right.
Great, he doesn't
remember you.
Not great.
Arthur Hobbs
hating Marshall,
that's no big deal.
He hates everyone.
It's the people
he doesn't know
that he cuts loose.
He just fired
What's-His-Face.
He fired
What's-His-Face, Ted,
and What's-His-Face
was invaluable.
Look, I can understand
you getting upset,
but it's not worth
killing yourself over.
Yeah, wait till
you get laid off,
then kill yourself.
Like What's-His-Face.
Although I guess now it's
more like Where's-His-Face.
Look, it was just
two cigarettes, okay?
I can handle two.
As long as I don't
have three within
24 hours,
then I'm not going
to get hooked again.
What's Lily going to say
when she finds out you smoked?
Lily's not going to find out.
I have a system.
OLDER TED:
Ah, yes, Marshall's system.
Hey, Lil.
You smoked.
Damn it!
OLDER TED: The next morning,
your Aunt Robin was thrilled
to be finally going on
the air with a real pro.
In three, two, one...
Hi, I'm Robin Scherbatsky.
And I am Don Frank.
Two teens were
arrested late last night
for stealing a police cart.
No, I'm sorry, not
a police cart,
a police car.
(LAUGHING) Screw it.
Brain fart.
Don't you hate those?
Look at that,
the teleprompter's
still running.
Something about a woman
giving birth on an uptown bus.
Well, no point in
jumping in halfway.
I'll just wait
till it's done.
(GIGGLING NERVOUSLY)
And she
cut the cord
with a Metro Pass.
We'll be right back.
And we're clear.
What the hell was that?
Don, you said "brain fart."
Look, Robin,
you seem like a nice kid,
but this is my 39th
local news show, okay?
And in that time,
I've learned three things:
avoid the all-you-can-eat
sushi buffet in Bismarck,
do not go to the bathroom
with your lapel mic still on,
and three, at this hour,
your entire viewing audience
is one half-drunk slob
sitting in his
underwear, so...
MIKE: Back in five, four...
Well, let's
do a great show for
that half-drunk slob.
Well, that half-drunk
slob appreciates it.
OLDER TED: The next day,
Marshall found himself
craving a cigarette.
It was driving him crazy,
so he decided to get
some fresh air.
Oh, no. You're not
up here to jump,
are you?
No, no, no, no.
I fired a lot
of people today.
I don't
need another
jumper in my file.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, uh, cigarette?
No. No, thank you.
That's too bad.
You know what
I miss, Jeffrey?
Getting to know
somebody over a smoke.
People are so
interchangeable now,
but you share a butt with
somebody, you got a real bond.
You know what?
I will take one.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm Marshall, by the way.
It's Marshall,
Marshall Eriksen. Yeah.
Tell me something,
Marshall Eriksen.
How would you
like to see a picture of
the cutest dog in the world?
There he is.
He's a good boy.
Hey.
You smoked.
Yes, I smoked, and it
was my third of the day.
You know what that means?
I'm a smoker now.
It's all over.
I even bought a pack on the
way home and a lighter and
a Vikings lamp,
which has nothing
to do with anything,
but I saw it in
the window and
I liked it.
Damn it, Marshall.
We already have four
Vikings lamps and
smoking kills.
It was a way to
bond with my boss, okay?
You should have
seen me up there.
That is a cute dog.
Yeah.
Are those your kids?
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
Hey, look what
I got at the mall.
(CHUCKLING)
There he is. There he is.
Go ahead, you can pet him now.
No.
Yeah, yeah, come on,
he likes it.
Scratch him
under the chin.
(BARKS)
(LAUGHING)
I don't care
what your reasons are.
You know how I
feel about smoking.
Now, give me the cigarettes.
And the lighter.
Ah! That's the stuff.
What?
OLDER TED: Oh, yeah,
add your Aunt Lily
to the list.
Whenever Uncle Marshall
fell off the wagon,
your Aunt Lily got dragged
right down with him.
What you doing?
(SIGHING) If you must know,
I am reaching out to City Hall
to try to get the mayor
on our show.
Oh, my goodness,
you are adorable,
but the
mayor's not coming
on a show nobody watches.
My colonoscopy had
more viewers than
this show.
At least that had
some twists and turns.
Okay, you know,
I don't know why
you're acting like this.
I mean, maybe you're just
bitter because you never
had a shot at a network job,
but I think I still do,
so I really need to focus.
I've been on a network.
You were on a network?
It was
the best Labor Day
weekend of my life.
When you do the news,
you're in these
ergonomic chairs.
It feels like
you're sitting on a cloud.
Which was nice
'cause it was right
after my colonoscopy.
And the dressing rooms... Oh.
There's dressing rooms?
You bet your sweet headset
there's dressing rooms, Mike.
No changing
in the KFC bathroom
across the street. No, sir.
It was heaven.
But the second
you get used to it,
they go find
someone who isn't "going
through a bitter divorce"
and doesn't "reek of gin,"
and before you know it,
you're stuck in
a dead-end gig,
surrounded by
people going nowhere,
doing the news in
your tighty whities.
Okay, the underwear
thing was your choice,
and I don't like
that it's catching on.
Ah! Looking good, fellows.
Feels good, right?
God, I want to kill him.
Of course people watch
the show.
You guys watch the show,
that's, like, two right there.
Oh, my God.
You guys still
haven't seen my show.
What? We never miss it.
We've seen it!
Really? What color is the set?
(BOTH STUTTERING)
It's black.
Right. Yeah.
With, like,
silver around the edges.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Not your TV set,
my show set.
BOTH: Oh!
God, if I can't even get
my best friends to watch,
who's going to watch?
Lots of people.
You got bedridden insomniacs.
Bums camping outside
a department store.
People waiting in the ER,
where the TV is in a cage,
so you can't
change the channel.
Do you have any stalkers?
Yeah, but
even Leonard
won't watch my show.
I can't believe those guys
are smoking out there.
It's freezing out.
Remember when you used
to be able to smoke
in bars?
TED: Hey, dude.
I think that hot girl
over there's smiling at me.
BARNEY: That's a chair.
But yeah, dude, hit that.
MARSHALL: Guys?
Marco!
TED: Polo!
BARNEY: Polo!
Well, it's dividing our group
into smokers and non-smokers.
And that's not healthy.
You're right.
Let's go have a smoke.
What?
OLDER TED: Yeah,
I'm not proud of it.
Look at you two. Smokers.
Just like the rest of us.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
I am not a smoker.
I only smoke in
certain situations:
post-coital,
when I'm with Germans...
Sometimes those two overlap.
...coital, birthdays,
to annoy my mom,
pre-coital,
on a sailboat,
the day the Mets
are mathematically
eliminated every year,
and, of course, wait for it,
'cause Lord knows I have,
pregnancy scares.
Why are you
smoking right now?
I'm always pre-coital, Ted.
You know, maybe
smoking's not so bad.
I mean,
at least it gets us
out in the fresh air.
Yeah, and
all the coughing
really works my abs.
I... (COUGHS) Am...
(COUGHS) Ripped!
(COUGHING VIOLENTLY)
OLDER TED:
But as glamorous as it was,
within a week
we all hit our
breaking point.
(COUGHING)
You okay, sweetie?
(IN RASPY VOICE) Actually,
baby, my throat's a bit sore.
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
So, I'm whapping
him across the nose
with the newspaper, right?
And my wife says,
"Come on,
you can't treat
your son like that."
I don't know.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
Michael, call 911.
Oh, my God.
Okay, yes, yeah, right away.
It's Marshall, by the way.
(ARTHUR SHOUTS)
Oh, my God.
I hope Arthur's okay.
Dibs on his office
if he's not.
We have to
quit smoking.
(IN RASPY VOICE)
Honey, you said a mouthful.
I wish I had never started.
I mean, I think back
to myself at 13 years old.
If I could only go
back to that moment...
I hate that
little bastard.
(IN RASPY VOICE) Me, too.
Okay, that's it. Let's quit.
Let's. Let's do it.
Well, I am proud of you guys.
I have heard how difficult
it is for smokers, like
yourself, to quit,
so, on behalf of non-smokers,
I salute you, and I am here
to help.
So, hand in your cigarettes,
and I will get rid of them,
one at a time.
(IN RASPY VOICE)
You're quitting, dollface.
I know
I don't normally
call you "dollface,"
but it kind of
works in this voice.
Dollface.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
I was just wondering,
is anyone else interviewing
the mayor tomorrow on TV,
or is it just me?
Hey, that's great.
Hey.
Yeah, Don can suck it,
while I suck this.
Light me, Marshall.
Actually, we've decided that
we're all quitting smoking.
That's fantastic.
I'm sick of you guys
bumming my cigarettes.
No, come on, Robin.
We can't do it unless
we all do it together.
No.
You can sleep with Marshall.
Oh, God, Lily, no.
Sorry, baby,
you got to take
one for the team.
I don't want to
sleep with Marshall.
I've seen the looks.
Right.
I can't quit right now.
Not before the biggest
interview of my life.
It's too stressful.
It's too stressful!
Just have one more.
Give me a cigarette!
No, wait! Robin, Robin,
think about this for
a second.
Bloomberg is
the anti-smoking mayor.
Do you really want to show up
to that interview smelling
like smoke?
It'd be like interviewing
a vegetarian smelling
like a McRib.
Really? Like I'm not going
through enough right now?
Look, you're quitting.
We're all quitting.
Fine. I'll quit.
Great. Great.
We just have
to get through
the first 24 hours.
After that,
it's a cakewalk.
(IN RASPY VOICE)
Barney, do you have
to bite your nails so loud?
I'm not biting my nails.
I'm trying to suck
the leftover nicotine
out of my fingertips.
Marshall, can you
pass the onion rings?
What, you
got dinosaur arms?
They're right here.
What do you
think cigarettes
are doing right now?
You think they're
thinking about us?
Dude, if you don't stop
tapping your foot, it's
coming off.
Oh, my God,
Ted, I'm so sorry.
Maybe I should move it
a little bit closer to
your ass!
I am ready to
do this right now!
Ted, I...
OLDER TED: None of us knew
what we were fighting about.
We just knew
we wanted to smoke,
more than anything
in the world.
(MARSHALL GRUNTING)
OLDER TED:
It wasn't going very
well for Robin, either.
Sorry I'm late.
Someone used
the microwave, and
the elevator stopped.
What are you doing?
Okay, Don. Don,
seriously, not tonight.
Okay, I'm a little bit
on edge
because I quit smoking
for my interview with
the mayor, so just...
Oh! Oh,
you precious little
porcelain unicorn, you.
(CHUCKLES) Why
would you do that?
Why?
Because I care, Don.
I care about the show,
I care about my career.
Unlike you,
you unprofessional jerk!
You're sloppy, you're rude,
and I wish you worked
half as hard
as the elastic on those
stretched-out underpants.
(SIGHS)
I'm starting to feel
like this is getting
a little personal.
No, Don, it would be
getting personal if
I would say
that the
reason you bounce
from market to market
is because
you're a loser.
A lazy, obnoxious loser.
The mayor canceled.
In five, four,
three, two...
Hi, I'm Robin Scherbatsky.
You think I'm a loser?
You're right. I'm a loser.
But at least
I've accepted it.
A plucky raccoon has
been cheering up patients
at a local
senior center.
I used to be just like that.
Always wanting more and
never getting it.
It's a dead end, Robin.
You're never going
to be a network anchor.
Just like you're never
going to quit smoking.
What are you doing?
I'm enjoying a cigarette.
Oh! That'll get you there.
That's good.
You want a drag?
Can we be professionals?
Please?
(LAUGHING)
Yeah. Professionals?
You know who's working
the camera right now?
A chair.
We're on a show
where we can't even
get the cameraman to watch.
That's why the mayor
canceled, Robin.
And that's why Mike is
on a fried chicken run.
And that's why you and I can
enjoy a cigarette right here
on the air.
No, thank you.
Why?
Because of
our millions and millions
of impressionable viewers?
Okay. If any
impressionable viewers
have a problem with this,
please give us a call.
The number's on the screen.
Chirp, chirp?
Come on, Robin,
live a little.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh, that must be Mike.
He always forgets,
extra crispy. Hello?
Robin, don't smoke
that cigarette!
Marshall?
We're all watching
and we're all
very impressionable.
And I swear to God, if
you smoke that cigarette,
we're all going to smoke.
You guys are watching?
(IN RASPY VOICE) We sure are,
sweetheart, and you look
fabulous.
Oh, you guys.
You don't
have to do this, Robin.
You don't have to smoke.
Resist it, honey.
Thanks for the call, guys.
(GASPS)
(ALL CHEERING)
She did it!
Good for her.
We're not going to smoke.
I have a pack
stashed up on the roof.
(BARNEY EXCLAIMING)
I'm awake.
And I'm smoking!
Robin, you know
how dangerous it is
to wake a sleep-smoker?
Dear God.
It's fine. I bought
a pack on my way home.
Hey, great show, Robin.
Yeah.
Yeah, but that Don guy,
what a tool.
Well, no,
he actually
apologized to me.
No, I mean when he stood up.
Those briefs were
pretty revealing.
You should
date that guy.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
Not in this lifetime.
OLDER TED: They were dating
within three months,
but more on that later.
Hey, guys, look,
the sun's coming up.
You know
what right now is
a perfect time for?
A last cigarette ever.
No, I mean,
a real last cigarette ever.
Damn it, let's do it.
Okay.
All right.
Last cigarette ever
on the count of three.
One...
...two...
...three.
OLDER TED: We all quit
for a while after that,
but it wasn't
anyone's last cigarette.
We did eventually all
quit smoking for real.
Robin's last cigarette
was in June, 2013.
Barney's last cigarette
was in March, 2017.
Lily's last cigarette
was the day
she started
trying to get pregnant.
And Marshall's last cigarette
was the day his son was born.
And my last cigarette?
Two weeks into dating
your mother.
And I never looked back.
(MARSHALL EXHALES)
I'm sorry I hit you, buddy.
I wanted to make it up to you
by giving you this.
Wow, she's hot!
Yeah. Well, some day,
you're going to marry her.
No way.
We're pretty lucky.
Totally.
I'll be in my tent.
Oh, no.
Wait, hey! No,
don't do that.
Well...
Have fun for me.