OLDER TED: Kids, your
uncle Barney had been called
a lot of names
over the years.
Jerk!
Bastard!
Barack Obama, Jr.?
Mmm-hmm.
And, yes. We can.
But there's
one name none of us ever
expected to hear him called.
Boyfriend. Barney
Stinson is my boyfriend.
I've said it,
like, 100 times.
It still sounds
weird to say.
Well, anything
sounds weird if
you say it 100 times.
Bowl.
But other than that,
things are good?
Bowl.
I don't know.
I think Barney's
been single for too long.
Bowl.
Like, the other night,
I wake up at 4:00 a.m...
(CLATTERING)
(GASPS)
Barney, are you awake?
Barney?
Barney. This is
not a one-night stand.
We're dating.
Come back to bed.
Bowl. Bowl.
That's happened three times.
And it's not just that,
it's other things.
Hey. What's wrong?
It was just one thing
after another at
work today,
and then I found out
my aunt's in the hospital.
I'm just...
I'm feeling so
overwhelmed and it's just...
(SHUSHING)
What you need to do
is talk through this stuff.
Thanks.
And then,
once you're off
the phone with Lily,
I'll be down in the bar
ready to have sex. Okay?
Bowl.
Look, I'm not
the touchy-feeliest
person in the world, but,
a little more
effort would be nice.
Bowl. Bowl.
I understand.
I guess,
in a lot of ways,
Barney doesn't stack up.
Bowl. Bowl.
I mean, you've had some
pretty incredible boyfriends.
Bowl. Bowl.
Bowl. Bowl. Bowl.
No, that's not it.
I don't know.
Bowl. Bowl.
Maybe he just
doesn't have it in him.
Bowl. Bowl. Bowl.
Maybe this whole
thing's a big mistake.
Bowl.
Bowl?
She really said that?
And she meant it.
Trust me.
I dated Robin for a year.
If you don't
want to lose her,
you gotta try
a little harder.
Be more attentive to
where she is emotionally.
You know,
just be present.
Yes, totally.
Yeah. Only thing,
and this is just me,
I like my testicles
attached to my body,
rather than rolling around
next to some eyeliner in
Robin's purse.
Stinson out!
OLDER TED: But then,
a funny thing happened.
Over the
next couple of weeks,
Barney was thoughtful,
considerate, sweet.
In short,
the perfect boyfriend,
which, to Robin,
meant only one thing.
He's cheating on me.
What?
Why else would
he buy me flowers?
He's getting
some on the side.
Come on, Robin.
Barney's not the type
of guy who would...
Go on.
Plus, he keeps
saying he's working late.
But when I call his office,
they say he left hours ago.
Well, that doesn't
prove anything.
Yes. Proof. Good word.
I'm glad you brought
that up.
Barney's briefcase.
He forgot it here
this morning.
And what do you
plan on doing with it?
We. We, you and I,
are going to open it
up and look for evidence.
Ted probably
has a sledgehammer
around here somewhere.
No! Stop! Stop!
Eye contact. Listen to me.
Robin Scherbatsky
is many things.
Friend, confidant,
occasional guest star
in some confusing dreams
that remind me a woman's
sexuality is a moving target.
But she is
no crazy, jealous
stalker-bitch. Let go.
Hey, I've been down in
the basement storage area
going through all the stuff
that Lily and I left behind
when we moved out.
I'm sorry, Robin.
We should've
cleared it out
for you much sooner.
There's a basement
storage area?
You're not upset. Good.
Baby, guess what I found.
That's great, honey.
What the hell is that?
Marshall got it in college.
He used it as a nightstand
for years.
Until we found out that
Lily was allergic to
barrel resin.
Barrel resin?
Just go with it.
So, you need a hand
throwing it out?
No, I'm not...
I'm not just going
to throw her out, okay?
Mabel's like family.
So, what are you
going to do with Mabel?
I want to
give her away to
a lucky new owner.
Do you know anyone?
Yeah, let me think.
Do I know any rodeo clowns?
That's weird, I do.
But even Lenny wouldn't go
near that mess.
Well, he's not
going to have
the chance
because I am
putting old Mabel
in the Bermuda Triangle.
OLDER TED:
"The Bermuda Triangle"
was the name we'd given
years earlier
to the curb right
in front of our building.
Whenever we wanted
to give something away,
we'd put it right there.
It was uncanny.
This is so exciting.
Right now,
there's someone
out there who has no idea
that tonight they're
going home with just...
Just the best barrel.
Well, let's just hope they're
not allergic to barrel resin
like Lily here.
Be cool, baby. Damn.
See you, sweetie. Good luck.
Bye, babe.
Now, can we please
get out of here?
Yeah. I'll grab my coat.
(GRUNTING)
Oops.
A college notebook?
Oh, my God,
he's cheating on me
with some college girl.
I knew there was a skank,
but I thought she'd
at least be dumb.
"Birthday, July 23.
"Favorite hockey team,
the Vancouver Canucks.
"Age 29, but tells
people that she's 26."
Oh, my God,
these are notes about me,
or some 29-year-old
version of me.
(DOOR OPENS)
I hope I'm not too late!
I want to
see the look of joy
on the new owner's face!
She's still there!
Okay, Mabel,
let's find you a new home.
Here comes a guy!
And he...
He just walked,
walked right on by it.
He's probably
rushing home to get
a handcart or something.
Yeah! Hey,
better hurry up, pal.
(LAUGHS)
What are you guys
doing with Barney's
secret Robin notebook?
Let me rephrase that.
Did you two ladies
lose some weight?
What do you know
about this, Marshall?
Why would
Barney have a notebook
full of information about me?
Well...
OLDER TED:
The truth was
Barney was taking a night
school class taught by me.
Welcome to Robin 101.
Why is
Ted teaching
a class about me?
It all started
a few weeks ago.
...rather than rolling around
next to some eyeliner in
Robin's purse.
Stinson out!
Stinson back in.
Say, hypothetically,
I did want to change who I am
to become a better
boyfriend to Robin,
which I do not,
what kind of changes
are we talking about?
Why... There's just so much
you need to know about her.
Okay, for starters, don't
ever cry in front of her.
Okay.
And whatever you do, don't
cry in front of her
four times.
Hey, guys.
What you talking about?
Fantasy football.
They realized they
couldn't talk about
this stuff at the bar,
and since you live with Ted,
they had to find
someplace safe.
So, Ted's classroom.
"How To Date
Robin Scherbatsky."
Lesson one.
Now, even though she
puts up a tough exterior,
what Robin really wants,
deep down...
I'm bored.
You said you wanted my help.
Can we draw boobs
on the chalkboard?
We did that already.
No, like, really big boobs.
No. Look, I need this, too.
I've only been a professor
a few weeks.
Being up here, it's...
It's good practice for me.
Can we have class outside?
No. What Robin really
wants, deep down is...
(CELL PHONE DINGS)
Barney.
What? I'm tweeting about you.
You should be flattered.
How do you spell
"blah-blah-blah"?
"H's" or no?
Wow, you were just, like,
the worst student in the
world, weren't you?
They said
I had A-D... Something.
Can we have class outside?
Barney, I'm only gonna
say this once, so listen up.
I love you and I love Robin.
And I want to make this work.
So, if you give me
a few weeks of attention,
I could give you
a lifetime of happiness.
Can you do that for me?
Do you think I should get
Sports Illustrated
for 70% off the cover price?
Can we have class outside?
I gotta
find a way to
reach this kid.
"Class number two."
"Top 10 Robin Scherbatsky
Facial Expressions and
Their Meaning."
Now, notice
the vacant eyes,
the pale,
queasy expression,
suggesting nausea.
What do these mean?
You guys just had sex?
(EXCLAIMING)
Wasn't me.
Dude! I worked really
hard on these slides, okay?
Can we just...
Okay.
This look is hunger.
If you ever see
Robin looking like this,
get some food in her quick,
or one of two things
will happen.
One. Weird,
out-of-context laughter.
Or two.
Spontaneously falling
asleep in strange places.
But the most important
facial expression of all?
That's a building.
Oh. That's for my class.
The Flatiron Building.
Fun story about it.
It was designed by Chicago's
Daniel Burnham in the
Beaux-Arts style.
This architectural gem...
Dude!
Right.
The most important
facial expression of all.
Whoa.
Flared nostril ridges.
Wide, unblinking eyes.
If you ever, ever see
this face, Barney, run.
And don't take
a picture of it.
She will punch you.
And you will cry for
the third time that night.
Which brings us to
an important point.
Defusing the bomb.
"Defusing the bomb"?
What does that even mean?
"Three Topics
to Distract Robin
From Being Mad at You."
Distract me?
That is so condescending.
These guys are really
starting to piss me off!
"Immediately
switch the conversation
to one of the following,
"unless you want Robin
to start throwing her shoes."
(READING)
What? That's not distracting.
That's just talking about
the story of a scrappy
little underdog team
that prevailed despite
very shaky goaltending
and, frankly,
the declining
skills of Trevor Linden.
(READING)
You have to
clean your gun.
My uncle had
a filthy, old shotgun,
blew both his thumbs off
trying to shoot a beaver.
You... You want
to distract someone,
make them watch my uncle
try to eat corn on the cob.
(READING)
Did you know that
before intercourse,
the male and female emperor
penguins bow to each other?
"Mr. Penguin."
"Mrs. Penguin."
Oh, God,
silly penguins,
acting all fancy.
(LAUGHING)
What were
we talking about?
Uh-oh,
looks like we got a taker.
Come on, dude.
You know you want to.
A guy like you,
beard, no mustache.
You're exactly
the kind of guy who
could use a sweet barrel.
Do it.
No. That's not
a fire hydrant!
For shame, sir. For shame!
I bet
you couldn't even grow
a mustache if you wanted to!
Neither can you, sweetie.
Well, he doesn't
know that, baby! God!
Ted's only
teaching Barney
horrible things about me.
I don't know. Check this out.
This is actually kind
of sweet.
Now, we all know Robin's
not what you'd call
"touchy-feely."
She doesn't
say, "I love you,"
like a normal person.
Instead, she'll laugh,
shake her head,
give you a little smile
and say, "You're an idiot."
"You're an idiot"?
Yup.
If she tells
you you're an idiot,
you are a lucky man.
And if she does say,
"I love you,"
she's already broken up
with you in her mind.
I think it's nice that
Ted knows you that well.
Yeah, well, too bad it's
next to a page entitled...
"Robin Scherbatsky's
Surprising Erogenous Zones."
Right knee. Ticklish.
Left knee.
Does lefty like that?
(MOANING)
Oh, yeah.
Lefty like that.
I can't believe I'm taking
sexual advice from Ted Mosby.
That's like taking
fashion advice from...
Well, Ted Mosby.
Here's a good one.
"Top Five Things
Never to Do Around Robin."
(SCOFFS)
Three. Never, ever play
the "Guess Who" game
with her.
What do you mean?
Guess who?
(YELLING)
(GROANING)
It's me! It's me! It's me!
Number four.
Unless you want to see it
80 times a day
for the next month,
never show Robin a YouTube
clip of an animal playing
a musical instrument.
Barney!
Do you
have a problem
with this class?
Yeah, it's boring as hell
and I'm not learning anything.
Well, maybe the problem
is your attitude.
You're not listening
to a word I say.
Uh-huh.
Can you hear this, Professor?
Or should I turn it up
for you?
OLDER TED:
It may not
have been a thumbs-up, kids.
So, you think you're
not learning anything, huh?
Okay. Pop quiz.
What...
When Robin's PMS-ing,
what kind of chocolate
should you get her?
Trick question.
Get her butterscotch.
Correct! Why?
Butterscotch is
to Canadian women
what chocolate is
to American women.
Correct! What is
Robin's dream job?
To become the most successful
female TV journalist of
all time.
Correct!
And if she achieves that,
will she truly be happy?
No! Robin's
deep-seated need for
attention can be traced back
to her father's
emotional distance,
and no amount of success
will ever make up for
what she truly needs,
which is six
simple words from her dad,
"Robin, I'm proud of you, eh?"
Yes!
(BOTH PANTING)
But I guess you're right.
You haven't
learned anything.
Sorry to have
wasted your time.
"O Captain! My Captain!"
How good was
Dead Poets Society?
I know, right?
The end? Tears.
Okay, can I just say
that my deepest need
in life
is not
to have my father say,
"I am proud of you, eh?"
Then why are you
crying right now?
I'm not crying.
Sweetie. Can I get
you some butterscotch?
No, stop it.
(BOTH SIGHING)
Wait a second.
It says
here that the class
meets at 6:15 on Tuesday.
So?
That's right now.
Now, as you can see,
well over 50% of
the blankets
have been dragged onto
her side. Make no mistake.
Robin Scherbatsky is
a classic, textbook
cover hog.
(BLEEPING)
Any questions?
ROBIN: Yeah, I have one.
Yes, Robin?
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
Flared nostril ridges.
Wide, unblinking eyes.
Uh-oh.
I got this. So,
emperor penguins.
Crazy, huh?
What the hell do you
two think you're doing?
Marshall, did you sell us out?
I was vulnerable, okay.
I said good bye to
a very dear friend today.
Dude, it's a barrel!
Aw. You're giving Mabel away?
Okay, I have...
I have so many questions.
Why would you do this?
What were you thinking?
Who the hell is that guy?
That's Shin-Ya.
He's sort of been
auditing the class.
Auditing?
Well, I tried to explain
to him it wasn't a real class,
but I don't think
he speaks much English.
On the bright side, he came
in handy standing in for you
during the role-playing
exercises.
Wait. You did role-playing
exercises where I was
played by Shin-Ya?
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
You know,
I can't believe you, Ted.
You actually think you're
some kind of an expert on me?
Hey! He is an expert.
He's a great teacher!
(CLEARING THROAT) Kiss ass.
You know, half the stuff
in this notebook is
patently wrong.
Really? Name one wrong thing.
"Robin Scherbatsky's
Surprising Erogenous Zones."
Let me clear
something up
for you, Ted.
Does lefty like that?
Oh, yeah.
All right.
Don't want to
leave out righty.
Oh, no.
The right one's ticklish,
I guess.
But the left one, yeah,
I'm glad you're back there.
Because that is just
some sweet, sweet loving.
Noted.
That was a lie?
We had just started dating.
I was being nice.
(CHUCKLING)
And you. You know,
I got it
into my head this week
that you were cheating on me.
I even broke
open your briefcase
to look for evidence.
That is a huge
violation of my privacy!
Go on.
You know, in a way,
I was right. You cheated.
You can't get some crib sheet
on dating me. That's not how
it works.
If we can't figure out how to
be with each other in a real,
honest way,
I don't see the point of
even trying.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
What do you want?
Look.
All that stuff I told Barney,
it was personal
between you and me.
I'm really sorry.
I guess I'm impressed
by how much you remembered.
It's funny.
When you date someone,
it's like you're
taking one long course
in who that person is
and then when you break up,
all that stuff
becomes useless.
It's the
emotional equivalent
of an English degree.
I guess I just liked
the idea of putting
all my
Robin Scherbatsky knowledge
to good use, you know?
Well, since you
know me pretty well,
am I fooling myself
with this whole
Barney thing?
I don't know.
I will say this, though.
I've seen Barney work
very hard to get women.
I've seen him
work very hard
to get rid of women.
I've never seen
him work this hard
to keep one around.
I was going
to give him an A.
Well, B+.
Shin-Ya kind of
screwed up the curve.
Hey. Before
you say anything,
I am done with this
stupid Robin 101, okay?
Here, I'll get rid
of the notebook.
But there's...
There's something that
I did want to say to you.
Robin, I have been
with a lot of women.
Blondes, brunettes, redheads.
Big boobs,
small boobs,
medium boobs,
some boobs that were big,
but kind of in a bad way.
The point is...
Boobs that pointed in
opposite... The point is...
I'm really scared
that you're going
to dump me
and that's why
I did this and
I'm sorry.
You're an idiot.
You know...
Hmm?
That notebook does
contain a lot of
personal info,
and I think it
has my home address.
And your work address.
Whoa.
MARSHALL: Hey, guys!
If you
don't want the barrel,
can you sit somewhere else?
'Cause you're scaring away
potential takers.
Designed by Chicago's
Daniel Burnham in the
Beaux-Arts style,
this architectural gem
was the first of its kind...
Professor Mosby?
Yes, Susan?
That's a woman drinking beer
on the toilet.
Right. That... That
was Daniel Burnham's wife.
She was
a troubled, troubled
woman. We are moving on.