OLDER TED: Kids,
you may be wondering
how many of these stories
I'm telling you are true.
It's a fair question.
After all, there's a fine line
between a good story and
a bald-faced lie.
I never met anyone
who could work that line
better than your Uncle Barney.
Heck, he could
jump rope with it.
I love to
travel myself.
Really?
Hmm.
Where's the best
place you've visited?
Hawaii's nice.
A buddy of mine
lives in Seattle,
that's a good spot.
But the best place,
I'd have to say
the moon.
Hi, Neil Armstrong.
No! You did not
convince a girl you were the
first man to walk on the moon!
That happened seven years
before you were born.
Ted, baby doll, minor hurdle.
Oh, yeah, our spaceship
passed through a wormhole
or some gamma
rays or something.
I started
aging backwards,
blah, blah, blah.
So, you work
in a yogurt shop,
that must be wild.
(ALL GROANING)
Although, I did actually
work in a yogurt store
in high school.
And it was indeed wild.
Anywho, 20 minutes later,
the eagle landed.
We knocked space boots.
Houston, we have a moaner.
Other space
related double entendres.
Why do you feel
the need to lie
all the time?
I'm not lying!
Guys, we made sweet love.
I got pictures.
No.
(SIGHING)
I hate my job.
What are you
talking about?
I thought you just
interviewed the mayor.
Mayor McWoof.
He wears a dog costume,
and teaches kids
not to litter.
At least
he's supposed to.
I don't want to
talk about Mayor McWoof.
I want to talk about these
amazing insoles from
Bon Appe-Feet!
Just look how
shock absorbent they are!
A prop!
The table's a prop!
(SIGHING)
We'll be right back.
Oh! Sorry, Robin.
Got bored.
Yeah, I don't blame you.
Man, just one
decent interview would
be so nice for a change.
Fine. I'll look at
my schedule,
see when I'm available.
But I want a list of
questions ahead of time,
and my personal
life is off limits.
Ted, you caught
seven peanuts
in a row.
It's impressive but
it's not newsworthy.
You caught seven in a row?
Seven in a row.
Whoa!
But that's not
what I'm talking about.
No, I'm talking about
how I was selected to
build a scale model of
the Empire State Building,
for the largest re-creation
of the New York skyline in
the world.
Is that the thing you were
playing with the other night?
I wasn't playing.
I was working.
"It's you." "It's me."
"I saw you in the street."
"Are you Annie?"
"Yes."
Ted?
Are you acting out
the last scene of Sleepless
in Seattle with little dolls?
How long have
you been out here?
Ten seconds.
Yeah. Just the last scene.
Oh, Ted. Again?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Ooh! That's the pizza.
Baby, do you have any cash?
Oh!
You know, I don't...
I actually...
I don't think that
I should have to pay,
'cause I'm not
a fan of pizza.
(LILY GASPING)
What?
Marshall,
we've driven halfway
across the country
for a piece of pizza,
literally, hundreds of times.
I once caught you
eating pizza in
the shower.
Marshall,
there's a cartoon
of you on our coupons.
I'm not saying
Marshall's a guy
who likes pizza,
but last time he went in
for a physical, doctor says,
"Marshall, you got
to stop eating pizza."
Marshall says, "Why?"
Doc says,
"So I can examine you."
But seriously,
we kid because we love.
All right, look, the reason
that I don't have any money
on me
is because
I got mugged.
You what?
Can somebody please pay
Arthur, all right?
I'm starving.
How's your dad, by the way?
Better.
Good.
Oh, my God!
You got mugged?
Who mugged you?
Was he wearing
a black skull-knit cap
and a five o'clock shadow?
Did he say,
"Stick them up"?
Yes, Barney,
because I got mugged in 1947,
at the corner of Abbott
and Costello.
No. I was cutting
through Central Park
on my way home from work.
Watch it.
Don't get any closer.
It's cool.
It was completely terrifying.
"It was
completely terrifying."
What are you doing?
I'm rehearsing.
I'm gonna pretend
this happened to me later to
try and get some sympathy sex.
Barney, that won't work.
Will it?
Big time.
I'll allow it.
I can't believe someone
pointed a gun at my
Marshmallow!
I'm shaking!
I don't think I'm gonna
be able to sleep tonight.
Aw! Here, sweetie. I have
something that will help
you sleep.
(ALL GASPING)
Just stick this
under your pillow.
You'll sleep
like a freaking baby.
Robin, put that away!
It's not gonna hurt anyone.
The safety's on.
(GUN CLICKS)
Okay, you know what,
let's all just relax.
We don't need a gun.
I'd just like to forget this
ever happened and try to
move on with my life.
"I'd just like to forget this
ever happened, and try to
move on with my life."
This is great stuff.
I think I'm going to
add tears, though.
Listen, baby, I know that
it's scary, but look at me.
I'm fine, okay?
Can't we just
put this behind us?
That's gold.
But I'm gonna switch it
to "putting me behind you."
Baby, you don't
have to worry
about me.
I mean, yes,
I'm a little scared.
But I'm a New Yorker,
I'm not gonna let
this change me.
I've changed!
I'm a gun person now.
Clip!
Yeah, maybe we should
just take a break
for a little bit.
(IN HUSKY VOICE)
I said, "Clip!"
You want to get a gun?
Not a scary one.
Just a cute,
little pink Beretta
that matches these adorable
strappy sandals
I just bought.
By the way, our
new credit card works.
You don't need a gun.
Every statistic in the world
points to the fact that
it's safer not to have a gun
in the home than to have one.
Especially in our home.
You know how I'm always
accidentally injuring you.
Pretty easy, right?
(LILY SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Hurry up, baby.
The party's about to start.
Boo!
(SCREAMS)
Oh, my God, Lily!
I thought you were
going as a sexy cat!
I changed my mind.
And now you
want to bring a gun
into that equation?
I know, you're right,
but every time
I close my eyes,
I picture that guy
pointing a gun at you.
(CRYING) And you're
my whole world, Marshall.
If something
ever happened to you,
I would just...
Okay, okay.
I know. I know. I know.
Okay, look, I got
to admit something.
That mugging didn't happen
exactly the way that
I said it did.
Aha! So he was wearing
a black skull-knit cap!
Told you!
No, he wasn't wearing
a black skull-knit cap.
He wasn't
wearing anything.
Wait. So...
Watch it.
Don't get any closer.
It's...
It's cool.
He naked-muggered you?
I'm not
gonna ask where he
was keeping the gun.
Are we sure
it was a gun?
No, guys.
I was walking
home from work,
through Central Park,
and I stopped at the zoo.
Watch it.
Don't get any closer.
Oh! It's cool. It's cool.
(MONKEY CHATTERING)
You're telling us...
That you got mugged...
By a monkey.
I got mugged by a monkey.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You got mugged by a monkey?
Yep. I got
mugged by a monkey.
I was embarrassed,
so I made up the
other story.
But the point is,
Lily, you don't
need a gun.
(LAUGHING)
Forget about the gun.
We're on this now.
Wow, monkeys are
mugging people now?
It really is
a jungle out there.
(GASPING) Oh, my God.
That monkey
has our address.
What if he's in a gang?
I hope
he doesn't
do a swing by.
Why didn't you
just ask the zookeeper
to get your wallet back?
'Cause I saw
what the monkey
was doing with it,
and I didn't really
want it after that.
Hey, guys.
What's up?
Oh! Some new information
has come to light on
Marshall's mugging.
Oh, really?
Did they catch the guy?
Well, he's behind bars.
Well, where did they
find him?
I'm guessing
naked in a tree,
throwing his own feces.
Oh. I've seen that guy.
See, that's why I take cabs.
You know how they
caught him, right?
There was a tail on him.
There was a tail on him!
Okay, what is going on?
All right, Robin,
here's what happened.
No, no, no, no, no.
Let me tell it.
It's my story.
You see, young
Marshall was at the
zoo, eating a banana.
No, I wasn't eating a banana.
If you're gonna tell it,
tell it right.
You're right.
The banana was
on the ground.
There was no banana.
There was no...
Marshall, I apologize.
Truly.
Robin, here's what happened.
(MONKEY CHATTERING)
Oh, God.
Oh, God, don't shoot.
There was no banana!
Come on, Barney.
I know Marshall didn't
get mugged by a monkey.
Marshall?
That part he got right.
What?
Guys, this is not
an uncommon thing, okay?
In Thailand, in China,
in Costa Rica,
people get mugged
by monkeys all the time.
Monkeys are gatherers.
Because of their
inter-social dynamics,
having a predisposition
towards stealing
gives one
a genetic advantage.
You were mugged
by a monkey.
Maybe he was just curious.
Were you wearing a yellow hat?
Marshall,
in all seriousness,
this is a great story.
I mean,
can I interview you
about it on my show?
What? He gets
to be on your show?
What about my model?
No one wants to see a guy
come on my show and play
with dolls.
Okay, first of all,
that is not what it is.
And second of all,
you just had a guy
on your show
playing with dolls.
So, your dolls
are favored to win
at the Rhinebeck Collector
Awards next month.
Only if they
behave themselves.
Last year,
I found one of them
cavorting with a G.I. Joe.
(LAUGHING)
It's not funny.
What were you thinking?
What if you'd gotten
pregnant?
And you invited him back
for a follow-up interview!
Only because the FBI
asked us to keep him
occupied
while they
searched his house.
Come on, Marshall,
I need the story.
It's got everything.
Crime,
monkeys, no stupid model
of the Empire State Building
that takes up my
entire living room
and makes the whole
place smell like glue.
Come on.
Do this for me, as a friend.
It'd be fun
to see you on TV.
Yeah.
Okay, can you promise
to present it in a way
that doesn't make
a joke out of the fact
that I got
mugged by a monkey?
You got mugged
by a monkey.
Oh, my God!
I just got mugged!
What?
Is what I was saying
to this girl at
the bar earlier.
It was completely terrifying.
I just want to
forget this ever happened
and try to move
on with my life.
Oh, you poor thing.
Neil?
I...
Neil!
Lady, my name's not Neil.
It's Ba... (GAGGING)
Why are you calling him Neil?
Because that's his name.
He's Neil Armstrong.
The cyclist?
I thought you
were supposed to be
on a shuttle mission.
I thought you
just got mugged.
Okay, I can do this.
You see,
I was on my way
to the launch pad
when I was mugged.
And the mugger took
my space shuttle keys.
Nailed it.
Who's up for
a three-way?
I am!
Me, too!
(CHUCKLING)
And it was
the best three-way ever.
Strange, 'cause you look like
you just had two vodka tonics
thrown in your face.
You have
lime in your hair.
The story's better
with my ending...
Just... Okay?
So, there we are,
zero gravity.
The three of us wearing
nothing but space helmets.
ROBIN: Marshall.
And I...
You won't believe it.
I pitched
the monkey mugger
story to my producer,
and he loves it!
Oh! Wow.
Yeah. Yeah.
Really? Cool.
I mean,
who's ever heard of a guy
getting mugged by a monkey?
No one, except
for the good people
of Thailand,
China, Costa Rica, and
plenty of other countries
where monkey crime is
an extremely common nuisance.
Well, the best part is,
he said that it might get
picked up to go national.
Guys, this
monkey mugger story
could make me famous.
Me, too.
(STAMMERING) Guys, this
is bad. I can't do this.
So it'll be a little
embarrassing. So what?
It's not that.
Guys,
(WHISPERING)
I wasn't mugged by a monkey.
So, you weren't
mugged by a monkey?
No, I wasn't.
So, what you're saying is,
the monkey tricked you
into giving him your wallet?
No, that's not
what I'm saying.
So, you mugged the monkey?
Guys, there was no monkey!
It was a human being
with a gun.
Are you sure it
wasn't one monkey
standing on
another monkey's shoulders
wearing a men's trench coat?
Be about the right height.
No! I...
I just made that story up
so that Lily wouldn't get
a gun.
The truth is that
it never happened.
I don't buy it!
What?
You heard me.
I think you were
mugged by a monkey.
You just don't want
to go on Robin's show,
'cause you're afraid
it'll make you look
like a big joke.
Well, won't it?
The biggest
'cause it's so funny.
Well, it never
happened, okay?
And I can lie to you guys
about it, because you're
my best friends.
I am, but go on.
But I can't
lie about it
on national TV.
Ted, you've
known him the longest.
Is he telling the truth?
Ted, don't.
I can't tell.
He smells good.
I just can't tell.
Well, I'm still
saying it happened.
Maybe. But, Marshall, if you
didn't get mugged by a monkey,
you can't let Robin
report it on her show.
I mean, this could
hurt her credibility.
Oh, please. Journalists
lie all the time.
I'm sorry,
but I will believe that
Jack Palance is dead
when I see the body.
Okay, this may come
as a shock to you,
Barney,
but people don't
like to be lied to.
Wrong.
They don't like finding
out they've been lied to.
"Because a lie is
just a great story
"that someone ruined with
the truth." Barney Stinson.
Case in point,
what that girl
Sarah did to me.
You mean what you did to her.
No. I mean
what she did to me.
The truth is,
I'm afraid the
three-way story
didn't go exactly as
I said it did.
Nailed it.
Who's up for
a three-way?
Lisa, wait.
Yes, Neil?
You're Lisa?
Sarah, wait.
Look,
I'm not Neil Armstrong.
I'm sorry I lied.
Well, I guess I wasn't
completely honest with
you either.
I mean, I said that I was 28,
but the truth is that I'm
really 31.
And if
we're being
completely honest,
I went to the doctor the
other day and found out...
Thirty-one!
I was happy, very happy,
thinking that I had
nailed a 28-year-old
with some sun damage.
People want
the lie, Marshall.
They need the lie,
which is why,
as far as I'm concerned,
you were mugged by a monkey.
Just as sure as I
had that three-way.
I am
the greatest
in the world!
(CHUCKLING)
Barney,
is that the
three-way belt?
You know it.
Props!
Man, I slept
so great last night.
(SIGHS)
Can you believe
I almost bought a gun?
I'm so glad you got
mugged by a monkey.
Okay, you guys got me.
I was just nervous.
I got mugged by a monkey.
Yes! I knew it!
Wait a minute.
Now I'm thinking
you really weren't
mugged by a monkey.
Come on, Ted.
Why would he make
something like that up?
Yeah, come on, Ted.
Come here.
Okay, seriously,
what is that cologne?
It's intoxicating.
OLDER TED: So, late
the following night,
we all went to
the set of Robin's show.
Okay, Marshall,
now, don't be nervous.
What we're going to do is,
we're going to sit you...
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
Looks like something
covered by a sheet.
Guess if you
want to find out,
you're gonna have
to do a story on it.
You're gonna be
covered by a sheet
if you don't
get your stupid
model out of here.
Dude, what are you doing?
I don't think Marshall's
going to lie on TV.
And when he backs out,
I want to be there for
my friend Robin with
a story.
Or rather, 102 stories,
because that's how tall
a certain iconic
New York landmark is.
Now, I want to buy a gun.
Whoa, the monkey's here.
Surprise.
We thought it would help
the story to bring him here
so you could
face your attacker.
Yeah, because
of this incident,
we will be
sending Captain Bobo
to a wildlife sanctuary.
Ooh! I bet
he'll like it there.
No, ma'am. You see,
we'll be splitting him
up from his mate Milly.
They've
been together
for a long time.
His mate's name is Milly?
OLDER TED:
And then the
interview began.
Marshall,
in your own words,
describe what happened.
Well, I would...
I... I would
love to tell you
what happened, Robin.
But...
I'm just...
I'm so curious as to
what is going on
underneath that sheet.
Well, we're not here
to talk about that.
We're here to talk
about your mugging.
Right. Well, people get
mugged in New York City
all the time, Robin.
But how often
do you get to see
whatever's under that sheet?
Mike, can we get
a shot of that?
We'll be right back.
We're clear.
What the hell
are you doing?
Okay, Robin, I wasn't
really mugged by
a monkey, okay?
I just made up that story
so that Lily wouldn't buy
a gun.
So, you weren't
mugged by a monkey?
No, what are you
talking about, baby?
Of course I was
mugged by a monkey.
Great. Tell it to America.
We're back in five.
No. No.
No. Not back in five.
I wasn't mugged by a monkey.
Okay, that's it.
I'm getting a gun.
No, no. Don't get a gun.
I was mugged by a monkey.
Well, then,
Bobo here is going away.
Wasn't. I wasn't
mugged by a monkey.
Ted, do you have any idea
if Marshall was mugged by
a monkey?
None whatsoever.
Just tell me,
were you or were you not
mugged by Captain Bobo?
Yeah, baby,
just tell us
what really happened.
Yeah, Marshall,
just tell us the truth.
Come on, you promised.
(ALL CLAMORING)
OLDER TED:
And that's when
Marshall realized
there was only one
thing he could say.
All right.
Here's the truth.
I...
am going back to bed.
OLDER TED: And that was it.
We never found out
what really happened to
Uncle Marshall's wallet.
But we do know this.
Aunt Lily never got
a gun.
Aunt Robin's credibility
remained unimpeached.
And Bobo and Milly lived out
their days together in the
Central Park Zoo.
(SIGHING) Damn it.
All right, Ted, mike up.
Miked up and made up.
Red leather, yellow leather.
That wasn't
very satisfying.
When I tell everyone
at work this story,
I'm saying he was
mugged by a monkey.
And I'm gonna keep
the banana-on-a-string
thing. That was working.
Barney, enough with the lies.
You can't just tack on
a new ending
because you're
not satisfied with
how a story wraps up.
Oh, really? Well,
mark my words, Mosby.
Someday, you'll
be telling this story,
and you'll see it my way.
Doubtful.
OLDER TED: And then, kids,
you'll never believe what
happened.
The monkey got loose.
He's got one of my dolls!
ZOOKEEPER:
Bobo, come here, Bobo.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
He's climbing the building.
Bobo, come here.
I'll get him.
Is this really happening?
Sure is, Ted.
OLDER TED: True story.