NARRATOR: That afternoon
at the Farhampton Inn,
Aunt Lily and I
tried to check in.
Are you chewing gum?
You never chew gum.
You shouldn't chew gum
in here.
Nobody cares if
I chew gum, Ted.
Are you chewing gum?
Yes, she is.
She's chewing gum.
Ooh, can I have a piece?
Of course!
Great.
Thank you.
Okay, let's chew some gum
and get you guys
all checked in.
Ms. Aldrin, how many
keys will you need?
Two, please.
My husband's
getting in later.
Excellent, and Mr. Mosby?
Uh, just one, please.
Oh, oh, I-I see.
Oh.
Well, hang in there.
You'll find somebody.
Thank you,
front desk stranger.
I'm sorry, we just... we just
don't get a lot of singles here.
I mean,
look at this place.
It's so romantic.
Countless babies conceived
within these walls.
And one... grisly murder.
Now, are you sure
that you wouldn't
feel more comfortable
staying at a motel?
What? No, look.
I'm not some miserable,
lonely person.
Tell him, Lily.
It's a tough
weekend for him.
Bro.
We're here
for a wedding.
Ouch.
And he used to
date the bride.
Ooh, mama.
And he's the best man.
Devastating.
Could you please
just check us in?
Oh, your rooms aren't
gonna be ready for hours.
But in the meantime,
Ms. Aldrin, I definitely think
you and your husband should
check out the lighthouse.
It's a beautiful view
of the bay-- so romantic.
Oh, wow.
Here's the channel guide
for the TV.
Don't listen
to him, Ted.
(phone ringing)
You are not alone.
In fact, this
whole weekend,
it is going to be
nothing but me and...
Marshall!
Oh, thank God,
you're on your way.
If I had to be here alone,
I would kill myself.
Marshall missed
his flight.
He might not get
here tonight.
He might not
get here at all.
We...
only have a few
of these left.
Hi...
Linus.
Here's how this goes down.
If I'm going to make it through
this weekend without my husband,
I need you to hook a lady up.
Any time you see me
without a drink in my hand,
you put a drink in my hand.
Are you my guy, Linus?
So you want the Kennedy Package?
Bingo.
(phone rings)
Go for Barney.
Ah.
Thank you Linus.
Barney,
before you get too upset,
there's another flight
that leaves in five minutes.
You're getting on it.
I'm gonna try.
There is no try!
You're getting on that plane.
Hey, growth spurt.
If there is only one seat
left on this plane,
I will fight you for it.
And I'm a biter.
Marshall, whoever that is,
grab her carry-on
and throw it
into a restricted area.
I'm serious. Do it.
Do it now.
What? No.
Barney, are you...?
No, I'm not gonna...
That's... No.
There is no
"What, no, Barney, are you,
no I'm not gonna, that's no!"
This is a holiday weekend.
You're not gonna get
to New York by being nice.
So you're gonna have
to lose the whole Midwestern
aw-shucksy-doodles thing...
Shucksy doodles?
...and act like a New Yorker.
A pushy, obnoxious,
knock-the-other-guy-down-
and-take-his-hot-dog resident
of the greatest city on earth!
No can do, Barney.
I'm from Minnesota,
where there's plenty of hot dogs
for everyone.
Perhaps even too many.
But listen,
I'm gonna get to New York
without being a jerk.
Just get to New York!
I'll get to New York!
Nobody's getting to New York.
Not this weekend anyway.
There's a big storm
rolling up the East Coast.
All the airports
are closing.
My advice is
rent a car and drive.
But you better hurry.
They're gonna
run out of cars soon.
(groans)
Okay, listen.
If we're both
going to New York,
why don't we rent a car,
split the drive?
That seems like
a reasonable plan.
Can I help you with
that diaper bag?
Sure. Thank you.
Oh, it's...
Have a nice bus ride,
pumpkin head!
(panting)
Hey, lady.
Yeah, you just threw away
your ticket
to a really great road trip.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
You're all the way back there,
and I'm all the way
up here.
(laughing)
Oh, you can hear me.
Get ready to be driving
the jealous-mobile
because our car is
gonna have games,
snacks, a James Patterson
audio book
my mother describes as
"cluttering her glove box."
Your car? I'll be in Pittsburgh
before you get your car.
We'll see about that.
And if you're going to New York,
you're not gonna want
to go through Pittsburgh.
94 backs up around Allentown,
so you're gonna want
to stick on 80.
Jerk face!
Come on, universe.
I'm a nice guy.
Send me a miracle.
NARRATOR:
And then the universe sent
your Uncle Marshall...
Herm.
Okay, people, let's move
it along. What do you want?
You want a car? You got a car.
Beat it.
What kind of car
do you want?
Too slow, you get a minivan.
Next. Ah, midsize sedan.
Incoming. Next.
Yes!
You want a gas option?
Nobody wants a gas option.
Get out of here.
Next.
Hello. I need a car.
You've got it.
That's all of them.
We're all out of cars,
everybody.
Wait, no!
You let this guy beat you?
Ma'am, it's not a race.
That right there
is why you lost.
Maybe this is your fault.
Did you ever think of that?
Maybe if you
had just been
a little bit nicer,
then you would be
the one driving this lovely...
What kind of car is it?
NARRATOR:
Now, kids, I don't remember
the actual name of this car,
but to an environmentalist
like Marshall,
this car was a monstrosity.
2006 Monstrosity.
* Monstrosity
* 'Cause global warming's
not real. *
Oh, no, not a Monstrosity.
I'll take it.
I can't drive that.
I can. Give me the Monstrosity.
Do you have anything else?
I'll take the Monstrosity.
There's nothing else.
Give me the keys, old man!
It's just so freaking huge!
Well, actually it's
a Monstrosity Sport,
so it's a little smaller.
* Monstrosity Sport
* It's still freaking huge.
Fine. I'll take it.
But I'm also gonna need
a baby seat.
We're all out of baby seats.
Get out of here.
Oh, my God--
what am I gonna do?
I don't care.
(groans)
Can I make a suggestion?
I rent the car,
then I go buy the car seat,
come back here,
pick you guys up,
and then the three of us
drive to New York together.
(laughs quietly)
Let me get this straight.
So, you're gonna
rent the car,
go and get a baby seat
for my son,
and then drive all the way
back here to pick me up.
That's right.
Well, then you're
gonna need some cash. Here.
Hundred bucks ought to cover it.
So, we'll see
you soon.
You got it, Michael!
Marshall.
Doesn't matter now, does it?
Remember this day, Marvin.
Not only is this the day
that we either saw Prince
or a... a really flamboyantly
dressed greyhound,
it's also the day that your dad
chose not to be a jerk...
and put his trust in humanity.
Just watch where it gets us.
Shucksy-doodles!
NARRATOR: Uncle Marshall
was just about ready
to abandon
his faith in humanity.
But let's back up a little bit.
And now the true tale
of the Stinson Curse.
BARNEY:
Moscow, 1807.
(Russian accent):
What a wonderful night
at the opera.
Wouldn't you agree,
Comrade Barnovski?
(Russian accent):
I would indeed,
Comrade Jamesokoff.
But you know what made it
truly wonderful?
Being here with my wife...
the beet in my borscht,
the fur on my hat,
the only person I've ever
been attracted to, ever.
I feel the same way
about Kyle...
my plutonic friend
from work.
(clattering)
Is it just me, or did that feel
like we hit an old Gypsy woman?
Yep. Old Gypsy woman.
Good call, Barnovski.
Oh, well, she's just a peasant.
Home, Smirnoff.
Wait, she's
saying somethink!
(low, deep moan)
Hornier.
Hornier?
Sonobovich!
Did she just put a curse on us?
Eh, nonsense, brother.
Okay, let's go, Smirnoff.
Smirnoff?
Homina, hominovich. Mmm,
Smirnoff, I would climb you
like the Kremlin Wall.
What's happening to me?
Don't you see?
You're getting hornier, brother,
just like
the old Gypsy woman said!
Oh, hello there.
(chuckles) Ever had
a White Russian?
BARNEY:
For the next 200 years,
every male member
of the Stinson family
was afflicted
by the Gypsy's curse,
an unquenchable thirst
for booty
that no committed relationship
could ever satisfy.
That is, until my brother James
met his husband Tom.
The day they got married,
they lifted the curse forever,
freeing me from the shackles
of having sex
with lots of different women.
Although, sometimes
Robin and I still use
the shackles.
Bondage five!
Whoa.
I can't, I can't,
I can't.
(phone rings)
Go for Barney!
Ah.
Thank you, Linus.
This is worse
than I thought.
I know.
Showtime, no HBO?
JAMES:
No.
Tom and I are getting divorced.
What?
TED:
That's why you look
extra handsome.
I do get extra hot
when I'm single.
Your skin looks amazing.
Looks amazing.
I know.
So... so what happened?
Why-why'd you guys break up?
Well, the thing to remember
is that when something
like this happens,
it's nobody's fault.
You cheated on him.
Repeatedly.
I thought about
keeping it quiet,
but then I realized,
wouldn't my family want me
to be honest with them
about news this big?
Oh, can I just say five things?
What is the matter with--
sorry, six-- you?!
Ooh! What?!
I'm-I'm sorry
about you and Tom,
but you can't just drop
a bombshell like this
so close to
someone's wedding.
You broke the curse.
You and Tom
are the only couple
that makes Barney
believe in marriage.
(chuckles) Really?
The only couple?
I mean, no one else
comes to mind?
Been together 17 years?
She's a spunky redhead,
he's got calves
that launched a thousand
lady boners?
BARNEY:
Hey, sorry about that.
Hey, did you guys know
that Sunday is James' and Tom's
anniversary?
How cool is that?
We're anniversary bros!
Every year, we should go out
and celebrate...
just the two of us.
Listen, bro, you...
I know, I know, "Please, Barney,
you don't have to get us
an anniversary gift this year."
You get them an
anniversary gift?
Why shouldn't I?
They're the one couple
that makes me believe marriage
is possible.
I mean, I'm sitting right here.
Thank you, Linus.
JAMES:
Barney, the thing is...
Cover your ears and hum "The
Battle Hymn of the Republic."
Why?
It's for the bride.
Oh, it's for... (humming)
Okay, listen, James,
my cousin Vince
is a Mountie.
His girlfriend is back home,
but he gets gay at weddings.
He's yours.
I am giving you Vince.
Just please,
don't tell Barney.
If he finds out
that the only
successful marriage
in his life is over...
I hate everyone
at this table.
...it'll spook him.
I don't want him
getting spooked.
Robin, have some faith.
Do you really think what you
and Barney have is that fragile?
I don't want to find out.
Fine.
Thanks, baby.
No sweat.
Mmm...
So, James, seriously,
where's Tom?
He can't make the wedding.
He had his wisdom teeth out.
Ugh! On top of a divorce?
That is rough.
Uh-oh.
What is she talking about?
Tom and I are getting a divorce.
Excuse me.
Vince... off the table.
What was that?
I don't know.
It just came out.
That's it.
It's barely even noon.
You're cut off.
Thank you, Linus.
Okay, but after that one,
you're cut off!
No! No, you are not doing this.
Step away from the desk.
What are you talking about?
You just found out
about James and Tom,
and it totally freaked you out,
and now you're asking this guy
to point you in the direction
of the nearest,
dirtiest strip club.
Oh, well,
that-that's a tough one.
Uh, the nearest one
that's-that's kind of dirty
is The Sand Box,
but the, uh...
the dirtiest one that's nearby
is The Crab Shed.
Dude.
Sorry. Uh, but hey,
if-if you do go,
maybe you could take Ted.
I'm really worried
about that kid.
No, Robin, I am not
going to a strip club.
Especially right now.
Could you imagine
the day shift at The Crab Shed?
Robin...
I came to the desk to get this.
Is that the key to our room?
It's the key to James's room.
Oh, my.
What is that?
It's an erotic cake.
I wanted to surprise them
for their anniversary.
Is that... is that
James and Tom?
Mmm, caramel marzipan,
chocolate marzipan.
I love chocolate
marzipan.
So does Tom.
Used to anyway.
This is, uh, absolutely the,
uh... the weirdest thing
anyone has ever done
for their sibling.
I love you so much.
You thought I was
gonna freak out.
Well, I mean, a Gypsy
cursed your family
to become hornier and do
awesome guitar solos.
Can you blame me?
Look, am I bummed about James
and Tom getting a divorce?
Obviously.
But I don't need them
to make me believe
in true love anymore.
I've got you for that now.
Mmm.
Oh, man, now I gotta figure out
what to do with all this stuff.
Well, before we do that...
um, would it be all
right if I nibbled
on your brother's
Ding Dong?
How about we nibble
on my brother's
Ding Dong together?
I'd like that.
NARRATOR:
So, they cleaned all that stuff
out of there
and had a talk with James.
And Barney didn't freak out,
because here's the thing, kids.
When you believe in people,
people come through.
Just so we're clear,
I pick the music.
Of course.
Say it.
Say, "Daphne picks the music."
Daphne picks the music.
And you pay for gas.
Are you kidding?
Do you have any idea
how much gas this thing takes?
(engine revs)
No, no, okay!
Okay, I pay for gas.
Good. Now, get in.
It's a long ride to Phoenix.
Say what?
(laughs)
I'm just kidding.
Oh, this is gonna be fun.
This must be the singles table.
(chuckles)
Guess it is.
Well, it's kind of nice
to be asking this question
instead of answering it
for a change:
How are you doing?
I don't know.
I'm trying to be happy
for my brother,
but, uh... I guess a person
has a different
perspective on weddings
when he knows what's down there
at the end of the aisle.
It's not all
champagne and frosting.
Mr. Stinson, your room is ready.
And, Ted...
she's right around the corner.
Thank you, Curtis.
I feel it, too.
No, no, no, the-the housekeeper.
She's in the room that's right
around the corner from yours.
Oh.
So another hour, tops.
Sure.
Okay, see you later, Ted.
You're not
giving up, James.
And neither am I.
(footsteps approach)
TED:
Hey, beautiful.
Hi.
God, you look great.
What? Come on.
You do!
I've been in a car all morning.
I just ate a croissant crumb
that I found in my bra.
I'm disgusting.
Yeah, I saw you do that.
And it was super hot. Come here.
(chuckles)
You come here.
Come here.
No, you come here.
Hey, you want to hear
something funny?
Mm-hmm.
One year ago today,
almost to the minute,
I was sitting
at this very table
right in that seat.
Oh, yeah. I can see it.
Nursing your gin and tonic
with three extra limes,
doing the crossword,
probably being
all showboat-y about it.
I wasn't being
showboat-y about it.
"Vesuvius."
Boo-yah!
Oh, wait, that doesn't fit.
The point is,
one year ago today,
I made a promise to myself
right at this table.
THE MOTHER:
What was the promise?
BOTH TEDS:
I'm coming back,
and I'm bringing you.
Wait a second.
Hold it.
One year ago today,
you hadn't even met me.
I know, but I knew I would.
And now it's a year later.
And here I am.
Here you are.
Love in your eyes,
baked goods
in your undergarments.
Yeah.
You picked a real winner, Mosby.
I did.
Okay, seriously, what the crap
is taking so long
with these rooms?
It was like this
last year.
I'll be right back.
I'll be right here.
Sorry that took so long.
Please...
try to enjoy your stay.
I will.
Try to.
I will enjoy my stay.
Try.
Not gonna try.
Just... just gonna do it.
Good for you.
Not good for me.
No, just-just neutral for me.
Attaboy.
No, at not a boy.
It gets better.
I am fine, Curtis. Okay?
I enjoy and appreciate
the happiness of other people
whether I am in a relationship
or not. Okay? Curtis?
So just-just...
just go ahead
and give me my one key
because I am fine.
Oh, come on!
I need another drink.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org