NARRATOR:
Kids, it was two days
before Barney
and Robin's wedding,
and everything was going off
without a hitch.
TED:
Ah.
Been waiting for the
perfect time for this,
and, my friend,
that time is...
I saw you and Robin
at the carousel.
(bottle shatters)
Okay, there was
one slight hitch.
BARNEY:
She called me to help her,
and there you were
in the rain
holding hands with my fiancée.
What up?
Nothing up.
Everything down.
All parts of me down.
Look,
you were busy,
so I-I...
I went to the park
to help her look
for this locket
she buried years ago.
She couldn't find it,
she got upset,
I held her hand. End of story.
Cool! I just wanted
to air that out.
You know, bro to bro.
You're my best friend
and my best man.
Of course I trust you.
Oh, come on.
You don't have to cry about it.
(sobs)
It's not that.
That was a $600 bottle
of scotch.
(crying):
Oh, my God.
(both blubbering)
I hope Marshall gets here
for the rehearsal dinner.
Thank you, Linus.
He's somewhere in Wisconsin
in a rental car.
Hertz?
I mean, it
hurts a little
but I'm not gonna
cry about it. Hey!
We've been doing that
all afternoon.
ROBIN:
Oh, who's that for?
Marshpillow.
NARRATOR:
Kids, as you may recall,
whenever Marshall left town
for a few days,
Lily would compensate
with a body pillow
she dressed up
and named Marshpillow.
Pretty normal stuff.
But with Marshall stuck driving
across the country,
Lily decided to upgrade.
Meet Marshpillow 2.0!
Hey!
Am I on?
Hey, guys!
Hey, Marsh.
Hey, Marshall.
Hey.
It's like you're
really here.
MARSHALL:
Hey, Ted.
Can you give me a
gander of the environs?
Wow!
This place
looks beautif...
Wait for it.
He's frozen.
(Lily groans)
Same thing happened last night
at the worst possible time.
I had just gotten on all fours
and taken off my panti...
Now Lily's frozen.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
...ful.
This place
is beautiful!
Wow. Lily, it looks
like you really put
some time
into this, huh?
(chuckles)
Though I wonder if
instead of dressing up
your giant husband doll
like Malibu Ken,
you could've spent
a minute or two--
I don't know--
planning the weak ass
bachelorette party you threw me?
I-It's possible I forgot
to send out the Evite.
Robin!
Happy bachelorette party!
(chuckles)
You invited Patrice
to my bachelorette party?!
No.
You know, it's funny.
When I was planning
Barney's bachelor party,
I managed to wrangle
his boyhood hero, Billy Zabka,
from The Karate Kid.
But you scored Patrice.
I'm sorry, Robin.
I-I've just been so consumed
with our move to Rome.
I guess I forgot
to invite
the girls.
Yeah, Lily, I'd like
to show you how it's done.
Billy Zabka, what
a great guy.
Look at how thorough Ted was
planning the best man poker game
he's throwing for Barney.
Wait, I think I'm on some sort
of delay here.
(clears throat)
Best man visor
for the dealer.
Customized playing cards.
Barney's the king.
And...
the queens
are naked.
It was my first decree.
Hmm. Plus, Ted handwrote
all of the table cards
for the reception
in calligraphy.
The man's a wizard
with a pen.
Oh. I don't know
about all that.
Though I was approached
by the decorating committee
to make the...
signs for our senior prom.
I'm told they were
quite the hit.
(sucks air through teeth)
Hey, buddy, listen,
you're gonna kill me, but I
forgot to bring the table cards.
Uh, I'd hate to ask
you to redo them...
Say no more.
The best man is on it.
Thanks, Ted.
(scoffs)
S-So now the best man
is painstakingly handwriting
200 table cards,
but my maid of
honor forgot
to click "send"
on an Evite.
I didn't forget
to invite the girls
to your bachelorette party.
You have no girls!
(high-pitched):
What?
(chuckles)
What? I...
All my girls.
I gave you a list.
This list?
Yeah.
"Tall girl from work,
"mouth-breather
from coffee shop,
"average-sized
girl from that place"?
Ooh. Sorry I didn't
track her down.
She sounds great!
She's actually
kind of a bitch.
Face it, Robin.
You hate women, and...
women hate you.
Ted didn't go to his prom?
Classic.
While Lily was dropping the
ball as Robin's maid of honor,
the best man was busy
knocking it out of the park.
(sucks air through teeth)
Hey, buddy, listen,
my great-aunt Ida has corns
on her feet
and needs a first-floor room.
Uh, would you mind
switching rooms?
Say no more.
The best man is on it.
Thanks, Ted.
(shouts)
(whoops)
(sucks air through teeth)
Hey, buddy, listen,
the wedding doves
got here early,
and I don't know
where to put 'em...
Say no more.
The best man is on it!
Thanks, Ted.
(cooing)
Poor guys.
All cooped up.
I guess there's no harm in
letting you out for a bit, huh?
They carpet-bombed
my entire room.
Wish I'd closed
my suitcase.
And my mouth.
(sucks air through teeth)
Hey, buddy, listen,
I see you wrote "N-O-period"
instead of the number sign.
I'm worried that might
confuse the guests...
Say no more.
The best man is on it.
Thanks, Ted.
(knocking)
Here they are.
Freshly penned table cards
in a pretty decent chancery
considering I only
had my travel quills.
Wait. Why's the
poker game started?
Oh, um, the best man
moved the time.
Mm, no, he didn't.
Yes, he did.
Heya, Ted.
Thanks for the sweet lid, bro.
(quietly):
Billy Zabka's
your new best man?
He's the best... around.
Sorry, Ted.
Maybe next wedding.
W...
So you're playing the best man
poker game without me?
Tim Gunn's here and I'm not?
I'm Barney's personal tailor,
of course I'm here.
Plus, I've never
played poker before.
It looks like a hoot.
I moved into a dungeon.
I wrote hundreds of cards.
I even gave your batty
great-aunt Ida a foot massage
so vigorous it put her to
sleep right there in the lobby.
Yeah, I don't really have
a great-aunt Ida.
So you are mad about me
and Robin holding hands.
Of course I'm mad, Ted.
Holding hands is, like,
the fourth-grade equivalent
of banging.
Well, in your case, 12th grade.
Self-five.
You broke the Bro Code.
No, I did not. I only went
to help Robin as a friend
because you didn't show up.
I did not break the Bro Code.
It's in the text.
A bro shall not have
a weird moment
with another bro's fiancée.
Well,
too bad we're in Farhampton
and can't actually check.
I am pleased to announce
that the Bro Code has replaced
the Gideons Bible at select
hotels throughout the country.
Oh.
I'm sorry I said
you hate women.
Yeah, don't be.
For whatever reason,
I just...
(sighs)
I can't seem to connect
with them. Down!
Can you help me?
I've got
a bunch more wedding gifts
in the van.
Yay! I love Robin so much!
(quietly):
Oh, God, I'm gonna strangle
that bitch.
Robin, what is it
with you and women?
(groans)
They're so annoying.
I'm glad that you're
my only female friend.
Girls are always
whining and crying
over every little thing.
(groans)
(crying)
Yes. That's exactly...
Thank you. "Oh, oh, boo-hoo.
"Look at me.
I'm a sensitive
little girl..."
Oh. God, I'm sorry.
You're actually crying.
(groans)
It's just
so sad.
(sobs)
I can't be your only girlfriend.
Well, I...
I don't need anybody else.
I got... I got you.
For another six days and then
I'm off to Rome for a year.
(gasps)
What are you gonna do without
our Saturday morning brunch
with a side of sassy gossip?
A one-shot power play?!
Hey! Hey, Boston!
Why not drop your hockey pants
and actually take a dump
on the ice next time?!
(cackles)
I love it!
(groans)
See? It is just too horrible
to even think about.
Yeah.
You...
need another female friend.
(sighs)
Whenever I try to talk to women,
they look like they want
to punch me.
Well,
maybe you're accidentally
giving off the wrong vibe.
Like, what do you say
to other women at the gym?
Oh, well, I haven't been
to the gym in forever.
My metabolism is all messed up.
See, I can moose down a pint
of fudge ripple
for a midnight snack
and wake up having lost weight.
(groans)
Well, everywhere
except for my boobs.
So annoying.
You're gonna need a lot of work.
It's in here.
Somewhere.
I... It has to be.
Damn it, I know I should've done
these in alphabrotical order.
(groans)
Who cares about the Bro Code?
It's just some stupid book
you made up.
(gasps)
How dare you?
The Bro Code has been around
for centuries.
Nay...
whatever's more
than centuries.
Please don't launch
into a fake history lesson.
The Bro Code can trace
its lineage all the way back
to Broses himself.
Article one:
bros before ho's.
TED:
Okay.
I see what you're doing.
You can't prove that
I broke the Bro Code, so you're
just making up stories about...
This sacred text
was eventually brought
to the New World
in 1776 by none other
than Christopher Brolumbus.
Article 62:
a bro
who calls dibs first has dibs.
Oh? Dibs!
And that's why he got
to bang Pocahontas.
Pocahontas was
with John Smith.
Maybe
according to the hotel register.
Whatever Mrs. Brolumbus
didn't know
couldn't hurt her, am I right?
Well, except maybe
that New World syphilis.
But I digress.
Barney, if you believe
in the Bro Code,
how come you've broken it
so many times?
(gasps loudly)
How dare you!
I have never broken
the Bro Code!
Hmm? Hmm? Ah.
"Article 104:
the mom of a bro
is always off limits."
Okay, look,
we've all had a lot of fun
joking about me
banging your mom.
Not all of us. Continue.
But I swear nothing ever
happened between the two of us.
Trust me.
And what's going on
with your fingers?
(whispering):
That's how our bodies
were intertwined.
All right, this
is ridiculous!
It's ridiculous
that you won't admit
holding Robin's hand was weird.
It wasn't weird!
Yes, it was.
You know what?
We need a third
impartial bro to settle this.
To resolve this,
I really need to parse
the text of the Bro Code.
It's too bad
Marshall doesn't have a copy.
Actually, I do.
They were in the, uh,
seat back pockets on my flight
in place of the safety cards.
I'm also pleased to announce
The Bro Code is now available
in select airlines
across the country.
And Lufthansa.
Der Bro Code is,
like, huge in Germany.
Okay, so prove to me
you can make a female friend.
What about her?
Ugh! The girl
with the bangs?
Any chick who does that
to her hair
is going through
a big life transition
I don't want to hear about.
Next time, grow your bangs
long enough to cover your mouth.
Ha-pass.
Okay, well...
what about her?
Ugh! Comfortable shoes?
(laughing)
What, are you filibustering
later?
It's after 5:00.
Put on some heels.
Ha-pass.
Okay, well,
what about...?
Ugh!
I haven't even pointed
to anyone yet!
MARSHALL:
Now,
although not expressly stated
in the Bro Code,
a weird moment between
a bro and his bro's fiancée is,
in my bropinion... a violation.
No!
Yes!
However,
Ted was helping Robin
as a friend.
Therefore,
holding her hand
isn't necessarily
a weird moment.
No!
Yes!
That being said...
What?
(mutters)
...if we decide
that holding any friend's hand
is weird,
then, yes,
Ted did break the Bro Code.
So, the question
is this.
If Ted had gone to the park
and held Barney's hand,
would it have been weird?
No?
Yes?
See?
(scoffs)
It's not weird at all.
I don't know what to say.
Just be yourself.
Say something nice.
Which one? I can't do both.
Slut alert.
That's my 14-year-old daughter.
Crappy mom alert.
Ugh!
It's you. Nice bangs.
What is wrong with you?!
I can't do this, okay?
I was raised as a boy.
I don't get along with women.
Can we just drop it?
Okay, I never thought
I'd take a page
out of your fiancé's
playbook, but...
it's time to target
the crying chick.
Not weird at all.
BARNEY:
Marshall,
why are we
doing this?!
Two dudes on a beach
with a lifeless blob
they're pretending
is alive?
It's stupid.
So, I guess that means
Weekend at Bernie's
is stupid, too.
(gasps)
E-Lawyered.
Now, before
I can render a decision,
we need to recreate
the variables
at the carousel
as closely as possible.
Since Ted says
that he was comforting Robin,
he needs to do
the same for Barney,
so, Ted, comfort Barney.
I don't see how that...
Comfort... Barney.
(sputters)
Barney, what is
going on with you?
Why are you
so upset with me?
Marshall, this is stupid!
I don't...
Accept the comfort.
Fine!
(sighs)
I guess... I'm not
really mad at you.
I'm mad at myself.
I should have met Robin
at the carousel when she called,
but I was having such a good
time greasing 12-year-olds.
Laser tag.
Helpful. Continue.
Look, Ted, I'm sorry that
I've been taking it out on you.
You were just being
a good friend to Robin.
It's okay.
It would be different if
you still had feelings for her,
but you don't, right?
Right?
(thunder booming)
Okay, now it's weird.
You still have
feelings for Robin?!
What?! What?! What?! What?!
Okay, yes, sometimes I do.
Well, then, turn 'em off!
I would love to,
but it doesn't work that way!
I'm a... I'm a human being.
I-I-I don't have an off switch.
I'm shutting off.
There, there.
Sister?
Who needs a lady hug?
Ugh! What the hell
are you doing?!
Wait. Did you just
"ugh" my hug?
I don't need a hug.
I'm pissed off because
the Rangers just lost
to the Boston Bruins.
BOTH:
I hate the Boston Bruins!
(laughs)
Look, Barney,
I hate these feelings.
I hate myself
for having these feelings.
No one wishes they would go away
more than I do,
but I just... I... I can't seem
to make that happen. I've tried.
Well, then, try harder!
I'm marrying her
in less than two days!
What the hell are we gonna do
about this?!
NARRATOR:
As she watched Robin make
a new friend, Lily was happy...
for two seconds.
Oh, no!
Oh, come on, ref!
I haven't seen that much
hooking go unpunished
since my last
trip to Vegas.
And I was on that trip,
because we are best friends now.
(laughs)
(both laughing)
Hey,
this might sound
a little nutty, but
how about
we inject a sexual edge
into our abiding friendship
that...
BOTH:
...in no way jeopardizes
our emotional connection,
or respective marriages?!
(both giggling)
LILY:
Aw!
Hell, no!
Excuse me.
I've got a Boston Brewin',
if you know what I mean.
(laughs)
You listen, and you listen good.
If I see your face
around Robin again,
you will be crying
about a lot more
than your precious
New York Rogers.
Rangers?
I will cut you!
(Lily mutters gibberish)
Forgot my purse.
(mutters)
You know what?
That's why I only need you.
'Cause you're a psycho.
My psycho.
I am, aren't I?
Mm-hmm.
(giggling)
There's the blushing bride!
Back off, Patrice!
Look, Barney, the truth is,
it was weird at the carousel.
On some level,
it's probably been weird
between me and Robin
ever since we broke up.
But you're my brother.
I would never do anything
to hurt you, ever.
(scoffs)
I mean it, I swear!
I'll-I'll even swear it
on the Bro Code.
The Bro Code's stupid.
(gasps)
How dare you!
I'd be honored.
I can't promise that I'll ever
get to a place where it won't be
at least a little weird
between me and Robin.
But I don't want to lose you
as a friend, either of you.
So I will do everything I can
to move on and live with it.
The question is... can you?
(sighs)
I'm sorry, Ted.
I just... can't do this.
I fold.
What about the best man?
I fold, too.
I fold.
There goes my belly buster.
You sandbag all night,
only to bluff a couple
of rags, pre-flop,
and wind up
with a dry board.
That's what you get
for limping in shorts-tacked
with a pack of donkeys.
Muck city.
I fold!
Yeah...
Oh, right.
I knew that.
I knew that, I knew that,
Okay, two
players left.
You are bluffing, robot man.
I raise.
BARNEY:
Oh.
Hey, Billy, do you mind
pushing my chips
into the center of the pot?
Preferably with gusto,
because...
I'm all in!
Oh!
Oh, boy!
All right,
all right.
ALL:
Oh!
(cheering and laughing)
NARRATOR:
And that's how I became
Barney's best man again.
Everything was back
to going off without a hitch.
I'm coming for you, Mosby.
NARRATOR:
Okay, there was one
slight hitch.