Ooh, Chicago!
There is this pizza place
called Gazzola's.
It's fantastic.
It was closed down for a while,
but it just reopened.
I'm sure they got
a Godzilla's in New York.
We're not stopping.
It's just pizza.
Just... pizza?
Let me tell you
about the thing
you say is just pizza.
We begin with the first bite.
Oh, the crunch!
And then the marinara.
That roiling lava
of tomato and oregano--
it overtakes you!
I'm falling!
And that's....
when she catches you.
That chewy,
voluptuous mistress, Mozzarella.
Her oven-kissed cheeks crackle
with warmth in your mouth,
cradling the sauce
and the bread,
letting you know
that from now on...
this... is home.
This pizza...
is home.
If it was so delicious,
why'd they close it
in the first place?
Rats.
We're not stopping!
This road trip sucks!
NARRATOR: Barney's bachelor
poker game was winding down.
Tim Gunn, out.
Lily, busted.
Marshpillow,
fluffed and turned down.
We were playing what we thought
was our final hand,
and it was getting intense.
Action to Ranjit.
Ranjit, action to you.
What?!
Hey, Ted, thanks
again for your gift.
He gave us a framed photo
of all of us at the bar, and
he's getting us
two other wedding gifts.
What can I say? I just love
giving wedding gifts.
I love giving
wedding gifts so much,
I wish I could marry
giving-wedding-gifts,
and then get myself
and giving-wedding-gifts
a wedding gift.
Maybe saying things like that's
why I'm not married.
(laughter)
NARRATOR: Oh, you know what,
I should explain
why Lily was angry.
Six years earlier, a few weeks
after their wedding,
Marshall and Lily were going
through their wedding gifts.
Well, that's weird.
Did Ted get us anything?
Come on, Lily.
Ted... Ted's our
best friend.
If his gift hasn't arrived
yet, it's on the way.
Yeah.
NARRATOR: But time passed,
and no gift arrived.
Finally, Marshall started
dropping hints.
Hey, man,
it was great having you
at our wedding.
Thanks, Bro,
and thanks for this coffee.
It is great.
You were not wedding absent.
No, sir.
You were wedding present.
Do I detect a note
of hazelnut?
(laughs)
Wedding present.
I think he got it.
NARRATOR:
But I didn't get it.
More months passed.
His hints got more desperate.
Happy Halloween!
Yeah. What-what are
you supposed to be?
Well, I'm a wedding present,
Ted!
How could you not get me
a wedding present?
I mean, how could you not get
that I am a wedding present?
Get me? A wedding present!
Get me a wedding present.
Why isn't he getting it?!
I don't know.
Why didn't you
get the message
to dress up like a pregnant
teenager, home skillet?
NARRATOR: But he kept on waiting
until the summer of 2008
when I got engaged.
So Ted's getting married, huh?
Bet he'd love a gift
from his old pal Marshall.
Well, he can forget it!
We're getting them a gift.
But Lily, this is the dream.
This is the whole reason
we wanted Ted to get married.
So we could not
give him a wedding gift,
and he would know
exactly how it feels!
Baby, I'm as pissed as you are,
but we're getting them a gift.
We have to.
Fine.
We'll get them a gift.
A gift that'll send
a message loud and clear.
A gift-wrapping
station! (laughs)
Oh, boy. This time,
he ha to get it.
NARRATOR: And not long after
that, a package arrived.
Oh, well, well, well.
Package from one
Mr. Ted Mosby.
It's a little late, but...
What the balls is this?!
It-It's a thank you note
for the gift-wrapping station.
NARRATOR:
Which explains the face.
Wedding gift.
JAMES:
Hey, Barney.
I've got a wedding gift
for you, too.
Don't get married. (laughs)
Ah.
In fact, it comes
in His and Hers.
(in deep voice):
Don't get married!
(in high-pitched voice):
(laughing)
BARNEY:
Ah.
I'm not cheating!
Don't tell anyone!
I'll cut you in on half!
Hey, Barney,
can you ask James to stop
crapping all over marriage?
He's not crapping on marriage.
He literally drew this
on the toilet.
Come on, Robin. Please
don't ask me to pick sides.
In two days,
he's gonna be your brother, too.
Just be honest and tell him
what's bothering you.
Okay.
(imitating car revving)
Marshall, are you...?
Hey, Andretti!
Beat it!
Marshall, are you sitting down?
Well, I'm in a car,
and you were pretty clear about
the No-Teen-Wolfing
Now-That-I'm-A-Dad rule,
so, yeah, I'm sitting down.
Ted is getting Barney and Robin
three wedding gifts!
I hate him.
Lily,
requesting permission
to make a stink?
Stink away!
Hurry up and get it over with.
(window whirring down)
(phone buzzes)
Oh, that's Marshall.
I should take this.
Well,
call me Akira Yoshizawa.
World's most famous origamist?
I fold.
(overlapping chatter)
Barney, here's a good one.
What's the difference
between a Journey song
and a husband?
A Journey song has a climax.
(laughs)
I'm sorry, Robin.
I'm just messing with you.
Raise a hundred.
No, it's fine.
It's just funny hearing all
this anti-marriage stuff
from a divorced guy who
still wears his wedding ring.
What, this?
Mm.
Only wear it because,
nothing attracts a gay guy
faster than a wedding ring.
Except saying hi to him.
Or being in the same room,
or every app on my phone.
People, it is a good time
to be gay.
So you can just... you can take
that ring off anytime you want?
Anytime.
I'm all in.
And raise you...
one ring.
ALL:
Ooh!
Fine.
It's just a ring.
Okay, let's see
what you got.
Robin has three jacks, James
has...
just shy of a pair
of a sixes.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I'm gonna hit the gym.
Let me know if you want
to get some dinner later.
Oh, we'll give you a ring,
just not this one. Ho!
(laughs)
MARSHALL:
You, Ted Mosby,
never got me
and Lily a wedding gift!
J'accuse!
I did, too, get you a gift!
It was a coffeemaker,
and you never sent me
a thank you note!
Oh.
So-so... me-cuse?
You-cuse!
Robin, when I said, "Be honest
and say what's bothering you,"
I meant, stuff it down
and never do anything about it.
How did you not get that?
It's fine.
He's a grown-up.
(door opens)
What did you do
to my little boy?
(thunder crackling)
Hi, Mom.
You get your
brother's ring back!
Mom, please don't make me
take sides!
That's your brother out there.
You two shared bunk
beds and baseball mitts,
and, when you were hungry,
these supple breasts.
Arguably a little too long.
Stinsons stand up
for each other.
Take care of this!
I...
I'm gonna play
some cards.
All right, chumps.
I'm gonna tell you what I
told Frampton's guitar tech
when he couldn't find
a condom: let's gamble.
You gave us a coffeemaker?
Not just ah coffeemaker.
I asked what they used
at your favorite coffeehouse
and got you that exact...
one tier down model.
And you know
what you got me? Huh?
NARRATOR:
No thank you note.
So I started dropping hints
about it.
Do I detect a note of hazelnut?
Wedding present.
Kind of want to say thank you
to that note of hazelnut.
Thank you... note.
(laughs)
Wedding... present.
Anyway...
Thank you note.
Yeah, he got it.
But you never got it!
I drank so much coffee
that year,
hoping you'd take the hint,
my resting pulse was like
the drum solo from "Wipeout."
And then, uh,
Halloween rolled around.
Get me a wedding present.
On that note...
I think you'll like my costume.
Mm.
I'm a thank you note.
Thank you note.
Ah.
Guess you could say
that we sort of go together.
That's right, Marshall.
That's right.
When someone gets you a gift,
you give them
a thank you note.
That is how it works.
Give a gift, get a note.
Agreed.
Exactly.
I think he got it.
Yeah. Yeah, he got it.
I have to find a bathroom.
I didn't get it!
And I thought for sure
you'd get it
when I sent that thank you note
for the wrapping station.
"Dear Marshall and Lily,
"this is a thank you note
to thank you
"for the gift-wrapping station.
"Because even though
the wedding never happened,
"there's one thing that
didn't leave me at the altar,
and that's my manners."
I can't believe this.
Eriksens send thank you notes.
It's the one thing
that we always do!
We even have
a family saying about it.
"Lick it, before you stick it!"
"It" being the stamp
on the thank you note,
before you stick it
in the mailbox.
I will make this right!
I know, right?
Hey, listen, we're about
to go through a tunnel.
Guys, big dilemma.
My mom's insisting
that I get Robin
to give James his ring back,
but Robin's refusing.
But James seems like
he's really upset.
But Robin's
gonna be my wife.
But James
is my brother.
But Robin lets me do sex to her.
But I have
to spend eternity
in my mom's mausoleum.
I just wish there was a way
I didn't have to take sides!
What should I do?!
(exhales)
Choose your wife.
You always choose
your wife. Easy.
Got any other stumpers,
like how to answer
"Does this make me look fat?"
Well, maybe a little around
the hips but no more than usual.
You're getting married,
so I will deal with that
one after your honeymoon.
NARRATOR:
And she did.
Belize was amazi...
(groaning)
In marriage, being right is less
important than being supportive.
Remember: happy wife
equals happy life.
Wow, thanks.
That's some great advice, Lil.
I knew I could count on you.
He's gotten very respectful
with his fake listening.
Anyway, Lily,
I told Marshall this
already, but...
don't worry about not sending
a thank you note
for the coffeemaker. It's cool.
Uh, we did send a thank you note
for the coffeemaker.
Uh... no, you didn't.
Uh... yes, we did.
To Stuart and Claudia,
the people who gave us
the coffeemaker.
Uh...
what?
Hey, you two!
Hey.
Hey, thanks again
for that coffeemaker.
We use it all the time.
Especially when Ted's over.
Yeah, it's
a great machine.
We have one at home
and we love it.
Did I forget
to get you a wedding gift?
What kind of monster am I?
Mosbys always give
wedding gifts.
We even have an expression:
"Wrap it before you tap it."
You know,
wrap the gift
before you tap the person
on the shoulder
and say, "Here's your gift."
I will make this right.
Robin? Two things:
number one, are you
dropping heat right now?
No.
Great.
Number two.
(chuckles)
Nice.
Thanks. Anyway,
I came up with an amazing plan
that I think
will make everyone happy.
Step one: you let my mom win the
ring back in a hand of poker.
Step two...
No, that's all the steps.
What do you think?
So your plan is
you do absolutely nothing
to get your fiancée's back.
Okay.
Let me propose
a different plan.
Step one...
Good game, everybody!
(giggles)
And that's all the steps.
That's a really
pretty bra, Mom.
Well, I'd better leave now
before I lose
any more of my dignity,
the likelihood
of which
is increasing every moment
in this very chilly room.
Oh...
(door shuts)
Not good, Robin.
Very not good.
How do you
keep winning, anyway?
Well, to the keen observer,
all of you Stinsons have
the same very subtle tell.
Whenever you're bluffing,
you say the word "bluff."
Hey, I'm hungry. Uh...
should we get
some bluffalo wings?
Raise you $20.
When I walked in, I saw
an all-you-can-eat bluffet.
Raise $50.
Mmm... I could use
a bluffberry muffin.
A blueberry bluffin. Sorry.
A bluebluffy muffbluff. All in.
I don't believe it.
Robin, you've got
to give her that blouse back.
She loves that blouse.
She got those sequins from
Rick James...'s open casket.
Nope. Not happening.
Woman, as your bridegroom,
I command you!
We'll leave and
give you guys
some privacy.
(door shuts)
You, uh,
want to take back
that "I command you" thing?
Please can I?
Why is this so important to you?
Because it's my family.
And, so help me, you and I
will never have sex again
if you don't give back
their bluff.
Stuff! Damn it.
Look, I just...
I want to feel like
you're on my side
once in a while. That's all.
Look, I'm gonna
be your wife,
for God's sakes.
But, look,
if it's... if it's
that important to you, here.
Do what you want.
Thank you.
And please don't play
strip poker with my mom again.
It's all kinds of confusing.
(door shuts)
(sighs)
(phone ringing)
Oh, that's where
my phone is.
I wasn't eavesdropping.
Hey, baby.
Lily, we were wrong
the whole time.
Ted got us the coffeemaker!
He's a wonderful man!
What? No. Claudia and Stuart
gave us our coffeemaker.
Ted's a rat bastard!
Never mention his name again!
Your coffeemaker?
Ted got you that.
I was with him
when he bought it.
I don't know what to feel!
But Stuart said
he got it for us.
Stuart and Claudia
checked in.
I saw them in the lobby.
Let's go get
to the bottom of this.
Stuart,
no B.S., did you really get us
that coffeemaker
for our wedding?
Of course.
What a crazy
thing to ask.
They never give you enough
of these things.
Oh, my God.
Ted got us
that coffeemaker,
and you just played it off
as your gift.
You're a weasel. Admit it.
No, that's insane.
Really?
Housekeeping!
Conditioner thief!
Okay, shh, shh.
Yes, I am a weasel.
I ripped the card off Ted's gift
and I wrote my name on it.
Does Claudia know about this?
No. Please don't tell her.
That gift was a turning point
for us.
Ah.
I got to admit,
I came pretty close
to leaving you.
Bags packed, plane
ticket purchased,
topless pics sent to your
brother, the whole nine.
But seeing that you got our
friends such a nice gift,
ah, it just really puts
you in a whole new light.
Oh.
I'm a pretty great guy.
(water running in background)
And since that day, on the
foundation of that coffeemaker,
we've built a strong,
nurturing relationship.
Well, out of respect for your
marriage, I won't say anything.
Say hi to Claudia
when she gets out of the shower.
That's not Claudia. Good night.
Tap tap.
Look what I wrapped!
What?
(door opens)
(sighs)
So, I went to give James
his ring back...
Glad you came
to your senses.
You can't let being married
keep you from being you.
It's like Tom,
always telling me I spend
too much time at the gym.
Exactly. Is it so wrong
if you want to work out
a couple times a week?
Right. Or a couple times a day.
Or a couple times...
A couple times a day? Really?
A few hours before work,
a few hours after.
Only way to keep up
the chocolate xylophone.
(singing notes)
Still, that's a lot of time
at the gym.
Especially with two kids.
It's like
I always said to Tom,
"I've got to stay in shape
in case I'm ever single again."
And, hello, I was right.
Oh, my God.
I think I finally understand
what Lily was mumbling
in my peripheral vision earlier.
I'm marrying Robin
so I can be part of a team,
not just some guy alone at a gym
with admittedly amazing abs.
Thanks, Bro.
No. Thank you, Bro.
You're not getting this ring.
I'm always gonna have your back.
No matter what.
Thank you.
I love you.
Mmm,
I love you, too.
(chuckles)
(moaning)
Oh, oh! I almost didn't
tell you the best part!
There's more!
Really?
James, let me spell this out
for you:
now that I've got Robin,
we are not brothers anymore.
What?!
Uh-huh.
If you and
Robin are both
ever hanging from a cliff
and I have one hand free,
enjoy the fall.
Uh, buh-bye.
If you...
Oh, Mom! Good!
You should hear this, too.
This mother-son thing--
it's over.
It's been
a nice few decades,
but I've got a wife now,
so you mean nothing to me.
Oh, and me coming over
for Thanksgiving and Christmas,
that's done!
No more of that!
And you know why?
Because Robin said so!
This came directly from her!
See ya, losers!
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
Fiancé of the year?
(chuckles)
I think I know what's next.
Oh, God.
Oh, God. I can't leave this room
for the rest of the weekend.
I'm sure we can find
something to do, eh?
MARSHALL:
Ted, I'm so sorry!
No, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have spent the last
six years passive-aggressively
drinking gallons
of coffee around you.
And I shouldn't have taken
that sewing class
to learn how to make
that wedding present costume.
I regret all of it.
Me, too!
Except I actually don't regret
that sewing class.
I learned a fun and useful
lifetime skill.
But, seriously,
even without the coffeemaker,
you've given us more
than enough.
Well, there is one more gift
on the way.
Whatever it is, send it back.
(horn honks)
It's a little late for that.
Marshall Eriksen?!
Yes?!
I got your pizza!
Oh, Ted!
You are the best friend ever!
Don't say another word,
Marshall.
Save it for the thank you note.
You got it, buddy!
NARRATOR:
And, kids,
I got that thank you note
four months later.
Four months.
Uh, here's
your blouse back.
Is there any way
we could just, um...
forget about all this?
Oh, no, dear,
you keep the blouse.
Think of it
as your consolation prize.
Consolation prize?
You won the battle.
But I'll win the war.
Game on, bitch.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org